[NO SOUND]
[DUCKS QUACKING]
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
&gt;&gt; BEER -- SPARKLING, GOLDEN,
PURE, REFRESHING.
&gt;&gt; ♪ LIGHT, LIGHT, LIGHT,YEAH ♪
&gt;&gt; BEER IS AMERICA'S BEVERAGE.
PRETTY MUCH EVERYTHING IN
AMERICA THAT'S IMPORTANT IS
AROUND BEER.
&gt;&gt; BEER, NORM?
&gt;&gt; THAT'S THAT SUDSY, AMBER
STUFF, RIGHT?
&gt;&gt; YEAH.
&gt;&gt; YEAH, I'VE BEEN HEARING GOOD
THINGS ABOUT IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
&gt;&gt; YOU KNOW, AMERICANS LOVE
BEER.
IT'S LIKE, YOU KNOW, MOTHER,
GOD, AND APPLE PIE.
&gt;&gt; THE BEER IS CHILLED NOW, AND
INGRID SERVES IT IN THE
TRADITIONAL MANNER -- FROM A
PITCHER WITH A GARLAND OF
GREENERY.
MMM!
&gt;&gt; I THINK IN THEUNITED STATES ,
BEER IS THE EQUIVALENT OF THE
ADULT TEDDY BEAR.
&gt;&gt; THESE GUYS FIND THE KIND OF
RELAXATION ANDRELEASE THEY NEED
IN A COLD GLASS OF BEER.
FOR THEM, ONLY BEER DOES IT.
&gt;&gt; ♪ I THINK I'LL HAVE A COLDONE ♪
♪ I'LL TAKE ANOTHER BEER ♪♪ PLEASE, THANK YOU ♪
&gt;&gt; YOU KNOW, FOR THE LONGEST
TIME, WE DIDN'T HAVE CHOICES.
THERE WAS NOTHING BUT THAT
FIZZY, YELLOW, KIND OF BLAND,
EASY-DRINKING BEER.
YOU DON'T REALLY NEED TO THINK
ABOUT IT 'CAUSE THERE'S REALLY
NOTHING TO THINK ABOUT.
&gt;&gt; WE FIND YOURAMERICAN BEER IS
A LITTLE LIKE MAKING LOVE IN A
CANOE.
&gt;&gt; MAKING LOVE IN A CANOE?
&gt;&gt; IT'S FUCKING CLOSE TO WATER.
[ LAUGHTER ]
&gt;&gt; BUT NOW WE'RE SEEING MORE
CONSUMERS ARE SWITCHING FROM
MASS-PRODUCED BEERS INTO THESE
MORE ARTISANAL BEERS THAT ARE
BEING PRODUCED IN THE U.S.
&gt;&gt; WHAT ARE YOU GUYS DRINKING?
&gt;&gt; I AM DRINKING A BLUE MOON.
&gt;&gt; FAT TIRE.
&gt;&gt; SIERRA NEVADA.
&gt;&gt; ROLLING ROCK.
&gt;&gt; SAM ADAMS SUMMER ALE.
&gt;&gt; PABST BLUE RIBBON.
&gt;&gt; ANCHOR STEAM.
&gt;&gt; I'M DRINKING ARROGANT
BASTARD.
&gt;&gt; THE RENAISSANCE IN BEER IN
THIS COUNTRY HASBEEN FAR BEYOND
MY -- MY OWN WILDEST DREAMS.
TODAY, THE UNITED STATES HAS A
BIGGER SELECTION OF BEER THAN
ANY OTHER COUNTRY IN THE WORLD.
&gt;&gt; Baron: AMERICANS DRINK A LOT
OF BEER -- $97 BILLION WORTH
LAST YEAR.
THAT'S $6.55 MILLION GALLONS OF
BEER.
AND MOST OF THIS BEER CAME FROM
JUST A HANDFUL OF MULTINATIONAL
CORPORATIONS.
MY NAME IS ANAT BARON, AND I
USED TO BE IN THEBEER BUSINESS .
GROWING UP, I WANTED TO BE
PRESIDENT.
&gt;&gt; WELL, I'M NOT A CROOK.
&gt;&gt; Baron: NOT THAT KIND..
BUT THIS KIND.
WHEN I GRADUATED, I GOT A
CORPORATE JOB.
I GOT THE OFFICE,THE ASSISTANT,
AND THE COMPANY CAR.
[ HORN HONKING ]
BUT CORPORATE LIFE WASN'T FOR
ME -- TOO MUCH POLITICS AND
BULLSHIT.
SO, I ESCAPED THE CORPORATE
JUNGLE.
[ BIRD SQUAWKING ]
I HAD A CONSULTING BUSINESS...
[ TELEPHONE RINGS ]
...PRODUCED FILMS.
[ PROJECTOR WHIRRING ]
I EVEN GOT IN ON THE INTERNET
BOOM.
FAST-FORWARD TO 2001.
AN OLD FRIEND NEEDED HELP WITH
HIS SMALL, INDEPENDENT COMPANY,
MIKE'S HARD LEMONADE.
&gt;&gt; PLEASE WELCOME ANAT BARON,
OUR ACTING GENERAL MANAGER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BOOM.
I WAS IN THE BEER INDUSTRY.
I CAME ON BOARD AND ENDED UP
RUNNING THE COMPANY.
MIKE'S ISN'T OWNED BY A BIG
COMPANY AND ISTHEREFORE FREE TO
BE CREATIVE AND A LITTLE LIKE
ME, A LITTLE OUT THERE.
AND MIKE'S IS FUN.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING --
"WORKING IN THE BEER INDUSTRY?
NOW, THAT'S FUN.
THINK ABOUT THE PERKS -- ALL
THAT FREE BEER AND THE PARTIES."
NOT FOR ME.
I'M ALLERGIC TO ALCOHOL.
SO, IT WASN'T ABOUT THE FREE
BEER.
WHAT I LOVED WAS TAKING ON THE
CORPORATIONBEHEMOTHS WHO WANTED
TO SEE US GONE.
THREE YEARS LATER, I HUNG UP MY
HELMET TO PURSUE NEWADVENTURES .
BUT I COULDN'T FORGET THE BEER
WARS.
&gt;&gt; WELL, THE BIG BREWERS MIGHT
NOT BE CRYING IN THEIR BEER,BUT
THINGS AREN'T WHAT THEY USED TO
BE.
PART OF THAT COULDBE BECAUSE OF
THE EXTRA COMPETITION FROM THE
SMALLER GUYS.
&gt;&gt; THE CRAFT BEERS -- THEY'VE
REALLY BEEN ON THE RISE.
THEY'RE TAKING MORE AND MORE
MARKET SHARE FROM THE BIG GUYS.
&gt;&gt; SALES FOR THE KING OF BEERS
AND OTHER MAJOR BREWERIES ARE
SOFT -- 2% GROWTH OR FLAT,
LOSING GROUND TO THE WHITE- AND
BROWN-SPIRIT MAKERS.
THE REAL PROFIT CENTERS FOR THE
HOP CROWD ARE IN THE MICRO AND
REGIONAL BREWERY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THIS IS THE
BATTLEGROUND, ANDTHE HOLY GRAIL
IS YOUR WALLET.
ON ONE SIDE ISCORPORATE AMERIC A
DOING EVERYTHING IT CAN TO WIN
AT ALL COSTS.
ON THE OTHER SIDE ARE SMALL
BREWERS WHO ARE CHALLENGING THE
STATUS QUO.
BUT IT'S ABOUT MUCH MORE THAN
BEER.
AT STAKE IS THE AMERICAN DREAM.
AND HERE WE GO.
IT'S BEEN LIKE AT LEAST A YEAR
SINCE I'VE SEEN A LOT OF THESE
PEOPLE.
AND I'M JUST NOTQUITE SURE WHAT
KIND OF REACTION I'M GONNA GET.
IF YOU WANT TO FIND THE BIG
HITTERS OF THE BEER INDUSTRY,
THIS IS IT.
THE ANNUAL BEER-INDUSTRY
CONVENTION IS THEPOWWOW FOR THE
MAJOR PLAYERS IN THE BEER
BUSINESS, AND MY PAST
CONNECTIONS GOT ME AN INVITE.
[ UP-TEMPO LATINMUSIC PLAYING ]
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
BUT WHEN I ARRIVED, THEY DIDN'T
SEEM TO BE CRYING IN THEIR
BEERS.
HI!
&gt;&gt; ANAT BARON, RIGHT?
&gt;&gt; Baron: NICE TO SEE YOU, YES.
&gt;&gt; NICE TO SEE YOU.HOW ARE YOU ?
&gt;&gt; Baron: I'M GOOD.HOW ARE YOU ?
&gt;&gt; WONDERFUL.
&gt;&gt; YOU LOOK FANTASTIC.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THANK YOU.
&gt;&gt; HOW ARE YOU?
&gt;&gt; Baron: GOOD TO SEE YOU.
&gt;&gt; GOOD TO SEE YOU.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WOW, THE GANG'S ALL
HERE.
SO, WHAT'S NEW IN THE BEER
BUSINESS?
IS THERE ANYTHING EXCITING?
&gt;&gt; BEER WAS DONE OUT ON THE
SECOND YEAR IN A ROW.
THEY'RE LITERALLYTRYING TO STAY
ALIVE RIGHT NOW.
BEER HAS BECOME A COMMODITY.
&gt;&gt; IT'S JUST NOT THE SAME OLD
BASIC, DOMESTIC BRANDS ANYMORE.
YOU GOT TO BE INNOVATIVE.
&gt;&gt; WELCOME TO THE GAME.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THE NEXT MORNING, IT
WAS ALL BUSINESS AS THE BEER
INDUSTRY WAS SHOWING OFF ITS
LATEST AND GREATEST.
&gt;&gt; Both: "GET OFF YOUR BUTT AND
GRAB A MONKEY."
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT IS HOT-N-HARD
LEMONADE?
&gt;&gt; IT IS A MALT BEVERAGE WITH A
SERRANO PEPPER IN IT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IF YOU DRINK THIS, DO
YOU GET THIGH LIKE THAT?
&gt;&gt; IF YOU DRINK A LOT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: OKAY, GREAT.
WHAT'S HIS FAVORITE BEER?
&gt;&gt; OH, HE JUST LIKES TO "QUACK"
ONE OPEN ONCE IN AWHILE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: OKAY!
MEANWHILE, IT WAS ALL QUIET AT
THE ANHEUSER-BUSCH BOOTH.
IS THERE LIKE A HOTPRODUCT THAT
PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT.
&gt;&gt; NO.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT WAS THE LAST HOT
THING THAT YOUREMEMBER THAT WAS
LAUNCHED?
&gt;&gt; MIKE'S LEMONADE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: REALLY?
I HAVE TO ADMIT THAT I DID MISS
THESE GUYS.
BUT WHAT I DIDN'TMISS WAS BEING
IN THE TRENCHES OF THE BEER
BUSINESS, 24-7, IN A WAR THAT
NEVER LET UP.
&gt;&gt; ...CHALLENGING ENVIRONMENT
FOR DOMESTIC BEER RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE ALL FIGHTING TO GET A
BIGGER PIECE OF APIE THAT'S NO T
GROWING.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU THINK BEER IS
IN DECLINE, OVERALL?
&gt;&gt; ALL THE BIGBREWERS ARE DOWN.
THE DOMESTIC BEERSARE DECLINING
A LITTLE BIT MORE THAN THAT.
IMPORTS ARE GROWING SOLIDLY.
CRAFT BEERS AREGROWING SOLIDLY.
BEER IS ALSO FIGHTING AGAINST
WINE AND SPIRITS.
THERE'S JUST SOMETHING VERY...
UNCERTAIN.
&gt;&gt; Baron: HOW DID WE GET HERE?
HOW DID THREE COMPANIES COME TO
DOMINATE THE AMERICAN BEER
INDUSTRY?
THE FOUNDERS OF ANHEUSER-BUSCH,
MILLER, AND COORS CAME TO
AMERICA IN THE MID-1800s WITH A
DREAM AND A BEARD.
BY 1900, THERE WERE OVER 1,800
BREWERIES.
THESE DREAMS WERE CRUSHED BY
PROHIBITION, BUT THEN BUILT UP
AGAIN IN THE 1950s.
&gt;&gt; BEER AND ALE HOLDTHEIR PLACE
ON THE SHOPPING LIST TODAY,
ALONG WITH THE BREAD AND MILK
AND VEGETABLES.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WITH THEIR HUGE
MARKETING BUDGETS, THE BIG
BREWERS KILLED OFF MANY LOCAL
AND REGIONAL BREWERIES.
&gt;&gt; THE BREWERS ARESPENDING MORE
AND MORE ON MARKETING AND
ADVERTISING, DOING WHAT TOBACCO
COMPANIES HAVE DONE FOR
GENERATIONS.
WE SEE HORSES -- BIGONES -- FOR
BEER, BARS -- NICE ONES -- BEER
BASKETBALL, BEER SOFTBALL, BEER
VOLLEYBALL, EVEN BEER SOCCER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THE RESULT WAS
DEVASTATING TO THE SMALL
BREWERS.
&gt;&gt; THE GREAT AMERICAN BEER WAR,
A BATTLEGROUND OF CORPORATIONS,
CAREERS, AND CASH.
SINCE 1970, 35 LOCAL BEERS HAVE
BEEN KILLED OFF, DRIVEN OUT OF
BUSINESS, OR BOUGHT OUT BY THE
GIANTS, GONE FOREVER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BY 1978, THERE WERE
ONLY 45 BREWERIES LEFT IN
AMERICA.
AND THE GIANTS WERE FIGHTING
EACH OTHER FOR SUPREMACY.
&gt;&gt; MILLER IS THE COUNTRY'S
SECOND-LARGEST BREWER AND WANTS
TO BE NUMBER ONE.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH ISNUMBER ONE AND
WANTS TO STAY THERE.
&gt;&gt; NEVER WILL THEY KNOCK US
OVER.
&gt;&gt; WE FEEL THEY FEEL OUR HOT
BREATH RIGHT ON THEIR BACK.
&gt;&gt; BUT OUR MAJOR PROBLEM IS
MILLER.
WE MUST ATTACK THEM WHERE THEY
ARE STRONG, AND WE MUST DO SO
NOW.
&gt;&gt; AS THE QUARTERBACK OF THIS
TEAM, I CAN ASSURE YOU OF
AGGRESSIVENESS, DETERMINATION,
AND HUMILITY.
IT HAS BEEN CORRECTLY SAID THAT
WARS PRODUCE ADVANCEMENT.
WE NEED TO BE LEANAND HUNGRY TO
TAKE ON ALL COMERS.
&gt;&gt; WHO WILL OWN THE FUTURE?
WHO WILL OWN TOMORROW?
THAT DEPENDS ON WHAT WE DO
TODAY.
FOR US, THE ANHEUSER-BUSCH
FAMILY, THE FUTURE CAN BE OURS.
&gt;&gt; BY BECOMING MORE NIMBLE,
INNOVATIVE, FLEXIBLE,EFFICIENT,
AND ULTIMATELY MORE RELEVANT TO
TODAY'S CONSUMERS.
&gt;&gt; Baron: TODAY, ANHEUSER-BUSCH
SELLS ONE OUT OFEVERY TWO BEERS
SOLD IN AMERICA.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH IS A CLASSIC
AMERICAN STORY OF DEDICATION,
EFFICIENCY, AGGRESSIVE
MARKETING, AND UNBRIDLED
AMBITION.
&gt;&gt; WELL, YOU KNOW, IF ONE GOES
BACK IN TIME, A.B. WAS POWERING
AHEAD VIRTUALLY AT WARP.
AND THE SMALLER BREWERS,
INCLUDING MILLER, WERE
INCREASINGLY MORE AND MORE
VULNERABLE.
&gt;&gt; I LIKE COMPETITION.
SO I -- YOU KNOW, AND I THINK
MILITARY ANALOGY IN COMPETITION
WORKS.
WE TALK A LOT IN OUR OWN
BUSINESS ABOUT NOT ATTACKING A
WALLED FORTRESS.
&gt;&gt; THEY'VE GOT THE FIREPOWER OF
A WALMART OR OF A MICROSOFT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHILE MILLER MAKES UP
18% MARKET SHARE AND COORS 11%,
TOGETHER THE BIG THREE BREWERS
MAKE UP 78% OF THE U.S. BEER
MARKET, MAKING BEER THAT SEEMS
TO LOOK A LOT ALIKE.
CAN BEER DRINKERS TELL THEM
APART?
&gt;&gt; BEER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: [ CHUCKLES ]
&gt;&gt; I NEED BEER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IN FRONT OF YOU RIGHT
HERE, IN THIS VERYNONSCIENTIFIC
STUDY...
&gt;&gt; OKAY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: ...WE HAVE "A," "B,"
AND "C."
IF YOU COULD TAKE A SIP OF "A,"
"B," AND "C," AND THEN TELL ME
WHICH ONE IS THE COORS LIGHT.
&gt;&gt; I THINK IT'S "A."
&gt;&gt; Baron: YOU THINK IT'S "A"?
&gt;&gt; I THINK "A."
&gt;&gt; Baron: AND "A" IS...
&gt;&gt; "A" IS BUD LIGHT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BUD LIGHT.
ARE YOU SURPRISED?
&gt;&gt; YES.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT IS IT THAT MAKES
YOU A COORS LIGHT GUY?
&gt;&gt; UH...HABIT.
&gt;&gt; MY BEER IS MILLER LITE.
&gt;&gt; I AM A BUD LIGHT GUY.
&gt;&gt; COORS LIGHT IS MY BEER.
&gt;&gt; [ CHUCKLES ]
&gt;&gt; I'M GOING WITH "B."
&gt;&gt; "C."
"C" IS THE BUD LIGHT.
&gt;&gt; "B" IS DEFINITELY THE COORS
LIGHT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: SHOULD WE CHECK IT
OUT?
&gt;&gt; YES.
SON OF A...
&gt;&gt; Baron: AND "C" IS...
&gt;&gt; OHH, NO!
&gt;&gt; Baron: AND "B" IS...
&gt;&gt; NOT COORS LIGHT.
&gt;&gt; IT'S NOT "A."
I THINK "C" IS THE MILLER LITE.
&gt;&gt; OHH!
&gt;&gt; Baron: AND YOU PICKED THE
COORS LIGHT.
WHAT WOULD BE YOUR SECOND
CHOICE IN BETWEEN "A" AND "B"?
"B."
&gt;&gt; YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME IT'S...
&gt;&gt; Baron: "B."
[ WOMAN LAUGHING ]
"B" IS A BUD LIGHT.
SO, NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
&gt;&gt; I GUESS I FAILED.
[ LAUGHS ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: OH, NO, IT'S OKAY.
THESE GUYS DIDN'T FAIL.
BUT THE BIG THREE BEER
COMPANIES -- THEY'VE BEEN
SELLING SAMENESS FOR YEARS.
&gt;&gt; 85% OF ALL THE BEER IN THIS
COUNTRY IS REALLY INTHE FORM OF
LIGHT LAGER, AND OF WHICH
BUDWEISER AND BUD LIGHT ARE THE
BEST EXAMPLES.
THOSE BRANDS CONSTANTLY HAVE TO
BE RE-EXPRESSED TO A CONSUMER.
[ CRAB MOANS ]
[ SHEEP BAAS ]
[ ANIMALS GRUNTING, HOWLING ]
[ NOISES STOP ]
[ HORSE FARTS ]
&gt;&gt; OHH!
&gt;&gt; AND THE OTHER BEERS DID LOOK
ALIKE AND TALK ALIKE.
&gt;&gt; WITH INTANGIBLE THINGS LIKE
REFRESHMENT AND FLAVOR TO SELL
&gt;&gt; THE WHOLE BUSINESS AT MILLER
IS REALLY FOCUSED ON BECOMING A
GREAT MARKET.
&gt;&gt; LESS FILLING!
&gt;&gt; GREAT TASTE!
&gt;&gt; AAH!
&gt;&gt; WHAT WE ARE GOING TO BE
PURSUING IS -- IS A STRATEGY
THAT'S -- THAT'SDIFFERENTIATED .
&gt;&gt; OHH!
&gt;&gt; [ DOG GROWLING ]
[ DOG BARKS ]
&gt;&gt; BAD DOG.
&gt;&gt; AND NOT ONLY DO MOST BEER
ADVERTISEMENTS LOOK ALIKE, BUT
THEY'VE ALL BEENSAYING THE SAM E
THINGS FOR YEARS, TOO.
&gt;&gt; SO, WE'VE GOT TO CONTINUE TO
MAKE OURSELVES NEW AND
INTERESTING ON THE ONE HAND,AND
ON THE OTHER HAND, WE NEED TO
KEEP COMING BACK TO WHAT IT IS
OUR BRANDS ARE ABOUT.
[ ROCK MUSIC PLAYS ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: THE BIG THREE BEER
COMPANIES SPENT $1.5 BILLION
LAST YEAR TRYING TO CONVINCE
AMERICANS HOW DIFFERENT THEIR
BEERS REALLY ARE.
TODAY THERE ARE OVER 1,400
BREWERIES MAKING 60 TYPES OF
BEER.
TOGETHER, THESE INDEPENDENT
BREWERIES MAKE UP LESS THAN 5%
OF ALL THE BEER SOLD.
AND WHO ARE THESE BREWERS WHO
ARE CHALLENGING THE BIG THREE?
&gt;&gt; TAKE LEFT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: ONE OF THE FEW SMALL
BREWERIES TO SURVIVE FOR OVER
175 YEARS IS YUENGLING.
IN TODAY'S WORLD OF DAILY
TAKEOVERS AND CORPORATE
CONGLOMERATES,YUENGLING REMAINS
FAMILY-OWNED, WITH FIFTH- AND
SIXTH-GENERATIONFAMILY MEMBERS .
YUENGLING IS THE OLDEST BREWERY
IN AMERICA AND, UNLESS YOU LIVE
ON THE EAST COAST, THE OLDEST
BREWERY YOU NEVER HEARD OF.
ARE YOU GONNA TELL US WHAT YOU
REALLY THINK ABOUT THE AMERICAN
BEER INDUSTRY?
[ Deep voice ] YES, I WILL.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ Normal voice ] HI!
DICK, MEET DICK.
&gt;&gt; BACK IN THE '50s, EVERY
LITTLE BREWERY -- THEY ALL HAD
BEERS WITH PARTICULAR TASTE AND
CHARACTER TO THEM.
AND THE PEOPLE IN THOSE CITIES
AND TOWNS IN THATBREWERY'S ARE A
LIKED THAT BEER.
SO THAT'S WHAT THEY SUPPORTED.
AS TELEVISION BROUGHT IN THE
NATIONAL BRANDS, THE BEER JUST
GOT MORE BLAND AND MORE BLAND
AND MORE BLAND, TO THE POINT
THAT NOW THEY'RE IN TROUBLE
BECAUSE THE PEOPLE ARE SAYING,
"I DON'T LIKE THIS ANYMORE."
PEOPLE ARE FED UPWITH CORPORATE
AMERICA JAMMING DOWN THE
CONSUMER'S THROATWHAT THEY WANT
TO.
THESE ARE THE OLD WOODEN
TANKS...
&gt;&gt; Baron: WOW.
&gt;&gt; ...THAT THEY USED IN THE
1800s.
SO, WHEN THIS WAS BUILT, THOSE
WERE THE TANKS THEY USED.
THERE'S SO MUCH POTENTIAL WITH
OUR COMPANY.
I MEAN, I REALLY THINK THIS
COMPANY CAN KEEP GROWING AND --
AND BECOME A -- A LITTLE FACTOR
IN THE BEER BUSINESS.
WE'RE ONLY IN 10 STATES.
AND, YOU KNOW, WE COULD KEEP
GROWING, BUT IT'SGOT TO BE DONE
VERY, VERY SLOWLY AND
METHODICALLY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IN THE HISTORY OF
AMERICAN BEER, YUENGLING IS AN
EXCEPTION.
MOST SMALL BREWERIES WEREN'T AS
LUCKY.
&gt;&gt; IN 1978, THE BEER LANDSCAPE
IN AMERICA WAS PRETTY BLEAK.
IF YOU WANTED FLAVOR AND
DIVERSITY, YOU HAD TO MAKE IT
YOURSELF.
&gt;&gt; I HAVE A BATCH OF BEER THAT'S
FERMENTING RIGHT HERE.
IT'S CALLED OBA.
I'M PRESIDENT OF THE
BREWERS ASSOCIATION,WHICH IS AN
ASSOCIATION NOT ONLY FOR CRAFT
BREWERS BUT FOR HOME BREWERS.
IT TORTURES THE GRAIN.
IT'S A MALT STIRRER.
[ LOCK DISENGAGES ]
OTHERS.
I HAVE SOME HORNY DONKEY PALE
ALE.
ALL THOSE HOME BREWERS THAT
BEGAN MAKING BEER AT HOME
BECAUSE THEY'RE HADNO CHOICE ON
SHELVES STARTED DRINKING THEIR
HOME BREW, AND MAYBE THEY DRANK
ENOUGH TO HAVE DREAMS.
&gt;&gt; YOU GO, "WELL, IF I CAN MAKE
THIS BEER THAT'S THIS GOOD AT
HOME, I COULD PROBABLY START A
BUSINESS.
WHY NOT?"
IN THE EARLY '80s, I REALIZED
THERE WAS NO GREAT BEER
AVAILABLE TO AMERICAN BEER
DRINKERS.
SO, MY OBJECTIVE WASTO MAKE THE
BEST BEER IN AMERICA.
&gt;&gt; WE STARTED IN THEBASEMENT OF
OUR HOUSE.
I ONCE GAVE A TALK CALLED "VISA
HAS BEEN VERY GOOD TO ME"
BECAUSE WE TOOK ALL OF THOSE
PRE-APPROVED CREDITS LINES THAT
CAME IN THE MAIL.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA GRAB A BEER.
&gt;&gt; WE MAKE ANGRY BEER.
AND ANGRY BEER IS AGREAT THING .
ANGRY BEER MAKES FOR HAPPY
PEOPLE.
YOU KNOW, I'M ACTUALLY ANGRY
ABOUT BEER A LOT 'CAUSE I SEE A
BEER -- "THEY EXPECT ME TO
ACCEPT THIS?"
"I JUST SAW THIS COMMERCIAL
WHERE THEY SAID THAT?"
UNFORTUNATELY, ALMOST ALL OUR
BEER KNOWLEDGE COMES FROM
BUDWEISER, MILLER, AND COORS.
IT'S AS IF ALL WE KNEW ABOUT
FOOD WE LEARNED FROMMcDONALD'S .
&gt;&gt; FOR THE BIG THREE, BEER HAS
COME VERY CLOSE TO BEING JUST A
COMMODITY FOR THEM.
THEY'VE DONE APPROXIMATELY THE
SAME THING FOR AVERY LONG TIME .
&gt;&gt; A COMPANY LIKEANHEUSER-BUSCH
IS 100 TIMES OUR SIZE.
THEY LITERALLY SPILL MORE BEER
UP THEIR PACKAGING LINES THAN I
MAKE ALL YEAR.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU KNOW, MY -- MY PASSIONATE
LIFE'S WORK IS THEIR INDUSTRIAL
WASTE.
&gt;&gt; I DO NOT CARE HOW MUCH BEER
WE MAKE.
I ONLY CARE HOW WE MAKE IT.
IF WE END UP LEVELING OFF, I
DON'T MIND, AS LONG AS WE NEVER
COMPROMISE OUR STANDARDS.
&gt;&gt; THIS IS A VERY TRADITIONAL
CHERRY LAMBIC.
YOU CAN SEE THE CHERRIES.
&gt;&gt; CREATIVITY SHOULDN'T STOP
JUST BECAUSE THESE INDUSTRIES
HAVE BECOME THESE MASS,
INDUSTRIALIZED, CONSOLIDATED,
INTERGALACTIC COMPANIES.
THERE NEEDS TO BE LUNATICS LIKE
ME THAT STILL HAVE THAT SAME
PASSION.
&gt;&gt; Baron: OOH!
&gt;&gt; DON'T WORRY. ICAN MAKE MORE .
&gt;&gt; Baron: [ LAUGHS ]
&gt;&gt; THAT'S WHERE THE TRULY
WONDERFUL PARTS OF HUMAN
CIVILIZATION COME FROM,IS THESE
LUNATICS AT THE FRINGE.
&gt;&gt; WE'RE KEEPING IT AWESOME.
&gt;&gt; [ LAUGHS ]
&gt;&gt; AH, IT SMELLS GOOD.
&gt;&gt; DOESN'T IT?
&gt;&gt; THIS IS KIND OF AMOMENT THAT
WE CHERISH, WHICH IS THE
BEGINNING PHASES OF ANOTHER NEW
BEER.
SO, THIS IS CHOCOLATE BEER.
&gt;&gt; GOOD ANGLE, GOOD ANGLE.
&gt;&gt; CHECK THE ANGLEOF MY DANGLE .
&gt;&gt; NICE.
&gt;&gt; THIS PROCESS IS REALLY THE
EQUIVALENT OF A CHEF'S KITCHEN.
SO, THIS IS WHERE YOU'RE GONNA
ADD YOUR SPICES TO THE BOIL.
♪ SOME CALL IT COCO ♪
I DON'T REALLY LOOK AT THE BEER
INDUSTRY TO TRY AND GET
DIRECTION FOR WHAT WE'LL DO
NEXT.
IF IT'S ALREADY BEING DONE, IT'S
NOT REALLY SOMETHING WE'RE
INTERESTED IN DOING.
&gt;&gt; ARE YOU READY TO DUMP THIS
SHIT IN?
&gt;&gt; THIS CHOCOLATE APHRODISIAC?
&gt;&gt; OH, YOU KNOW IT.
&gt;&gt; PHILOSOPHICALLY, I THINK
THERE'S A GIGANTIC GAP BETWEEN
WHAT IT MEANS TO BE A BIG
BREWERY AND A SMALL BREWERY.
BIG BREWERIES AREUSUALLY PUBLIC
COMPANIES.
SO, WHETHER THEY'RE MAKING BEER
OR SODA OR WHATEVER, THEY'RE
REAL GOAL AT THE END OF THE DAY
IS MAXIMIZINGSHAREHOLDER VALUE ,
WHEREAS OUR GOAL IS MAXIMIZING
THE FLAVOR OF WHAT WE'RE MAKING
FOR OUR OWN ENJOYMENT AS THE
PEOPLE MAKING IT.
&gt;&gt; MAN, THOSE ANCIENT HONDURAN
KNEW WHAT TO DRINK.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
&gt;&gt; YES, THEY DID. YES,THEY DID .
I STARTED HOME BREWING IN '93,
BUT RIGHT AFTER I BREWED MY
FIRST BATCH, I STARTED TELLING
PEOPLE, "THIS IS WHAT I WANT TO
DO WITH MY LIFE.
PRETTY. IT'S NICE.
TO START THE BREWPUB WAS A REAL
CHALLENGE.
I WAS NAIVE ENOUGH TO THINK I
COULD JUST GO TO A BANK AND GET
MONEY FROM A BANK TO OPEN A
BRAND-NEW VENTURE.
I WAS 25 WHEN I MOVED DOWN HERE
AND STARTED THE BREWERY, AND I
JUST STARTED, YOU KNOW, WORKING
ON THE BUILDING,SIGNED A LEASE .
AND THEN SOMEBODYCAME UP TO ME ,
AND THEY WERE LIKE,"YOU DO KNOW
IT'S ILLEGAL TO OPEN A BREWERY
IN DELAWARE."
I'M LIKE, "REALLY?"
WITHIN A WEEK OR TWO, I WAS
ARGUING IN THE FLOOR OF THE
SENATE AND WRITING MY OWN
LEGISLATION.
IT CAUSED A LITTLE ANXIETY AT
THE 11th HOUR, BUT WE GOT IT
LEGALIZED THREE DAYS BEFORE WE
OPENED.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
THIS IS WHERE DOGFISH HEAD
STARTED, SO IT'LL ALWAYS HAVE A
SPECIAL PLACE IN MY HEART, YOU
KNOW?
WE WERE LITERALLY THE SMALLEST
BREWERY IN THE COUNTRY WHEN WE
OPENED IN 1995.
OUR MOTTO'S BEEN "OFF-CENTERED
ALES FOR OFF-CENTERED PEOPLE."
AND WE WERE TRYING TO SELL $13
SIX-PACKS OF OAK-AGED MAPLE
SYRUP BEER IN 1996.
WE GOT OUR BUTTS KICKED FOR
AWHILE BECAUSE THEREWASN'T THAT
GREAT LEVEL OF KNOWLEDGE OR
EXCITEMENT IN OUR INDUSTRY.
THIS IS OUR DE FACTO"R"-AND-"D "
LAB.
AND WE HAVE A BUILT-IN TASTING
PANEL AT OUR BAR WHO TELLS US
WHAT THEY'RE EXCITED ABOUT.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH, COORS,MILLER - -
THEIR WEAPON HAS ALWAYS BEEN
ADVERTISING, AND OUR WEAPON HAS
ALWAYS BEEN WHAT'S INSIDE THE
BOTTLE.
THIS IS FERMENTED HONEY.
THE CONCEPT OF HONEYMOON CAME
FROM THESE KINDS OF DRINKS IN
AFRICA, WHERE, ON THE WEDDING
NIGHT, THEY WOULD GIVE THESE
DRINKS TO THE PEOPLE GETTING
MARRIED.
AND IT WAS A REALLY GOOD
CATALYST FOR GETTINGPREGNANT ON
YOUR WEDDING NIGHT.
&gt;&gt; [ LAUGHS ]
&gt;&gt; HONEY, STOP DRINKING.
&gt;&gt; STOP DRINKING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
&gt;&gt; WHEN I WROTE MY BUSINESS
PLAN, MY GOAL WAS TO MAKE
SPECIAL, UNIQUE BEERS AND SELL
THEM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I DIDN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT THAT
MEANT, IN TERMS OF DISTRIBUTION
AND HOW DIFFICULTTHAT WOULD BE ,
ESPECIALLY BECAUSE WE'RE IN
COASTAL, RURAL DELAWARE.
I NEVER DREAMED THAT WE'D GET
THAT BIG.
IT'S AN OBSCENE AMOUNT OF DEBT
THAT I'VE GOTTEN MYFAMILY INTO.
SO, PERSONALLY, WE BETTER GET
OUR STUFF RIGHT.
OUR BREWERY'S GROWING AT A
RIDICULOUS RATE.
THERE'S NEVER BEEN A BREWERY OF
THIS SCALE IN THIS STATE.
GROWTH IS A GOOD PROBLEM TO
HAVE.
EXTREME GROWTH CAN BE PAINFUL.
IT'S KIND OF A NIGHTMARE,
REALLY.
WE'RE ON PACE TO DOABOUT 40,000
THIS YEAR, BUT OUR ORDERS ARE
SUCH THAT IF WE COULD FILL THEM
FROM OUR DISTRIBUTORS, WE'D
PROBABLY BE DOING 50,000 OR
60,000 BARRELS.
SO, WE'RE WORKING THE BEJESUS
OUT OF OUR 50-BARREL BREWHOUSE.
WE'RE RUNNING THAT DAY AND
NIGHT, 24 HOURS A DAY, 6 OR 7
DAYS A WEEK.
SO, THAT THING'S MAXED OUT,
WHICH IS KIND OF SURREAL FOR ME
'CAUSE WHEN WE MOVED IN HERE IN
2001, ALL I HAD WAS 6 OF THOSE
100-BARREL TANKS.
I'M LIKE, "OH, WE CAN GROW
FOREVER," YOU KNOW?
"WE GOT ALL THIS ROOM."
AND IT'S -- IT'S GONE.
&gt;&gt; "ROCK AND ROLL" OR --
THIS ONE I LIKE.
&gt;&gt; "WE'RE MAKINGDAMN GOOD BEER.
CAFFEINE IS JUST OUR SILENT
PARTNER."
THAT'S COOL.
I CAN READ.
&gt;&gt; WALKING AND TALKING.
I LAUNCHED THE COMPANY TO FIND
BASICALLY THE CRACKS THAT THE
BIG GUYS LEAVE BEHIND AND OFFER
INNOVATIVE AMERICAN STYLES.
&gt;&gt; "BOTTLE ROCKET" -- I LIKE
THAT.
&gt;&gt; MOONSHOT IS REAL BEER WITH
CAFFEINE.
IT'S AN AMAZING EFFECT THAT IT
HAS ON YOU.
AND I'M GLAD I THOUGHT OF IT
FIRST.
I'VE PUT A LOT OF MY OWN MONEY
AND CREDIT ON THE LINE.
&gt;&gt; WE'VE PICKEDMOONSHOT TO SELL
BECAUSE IT'S A NEW ENTRY INTO
THE BEER MARKETPLACE.
IT HAS CAFFEINE IN IT.
AND THAT'S GOT A PRETTY GOOD
STORY BEHIND IT.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU NEED
ANYMORE.
&gt;&gt; OH.
WELL, THAT'S ALL THERE IS, AND
IT'S SITTING OVER THERE...
&gt;&gt; IF IT SELLS LIKE WE THINK
IT'S GONNA SELL,THEN IT'LL KEEP
A FULL FACE FOR THE TERM.
&gt;&gt; OKAY.
&gt;&gt; THAT'S ALL.
&gt;&gt; I WOULD -- I'DLOVE TO PUT UP
A SIGN SOMEWHERE, BUT...
&gt;&gt; WE CAN HANG A SIGN FOR YOU.
THAT'S NOT A PROBLEM.
&gt;&gt; LET ME ASK YOU -- WHAT
LOCATION IS GONNA BE THE MOST
VISIBLE AND HAVE THE LONGEST
LIFE?
YOU GO PUT UP A SIGNONE DAY AND
YOU GO BACK TO THATSTORE OR BAR
THE NEXT DAY AND IT'S DOWN AND
THERE'S ANOTHERBANNER IN PLACE .
THAT'S WHAT BEER WARS ARE ALL
ABOUT.
I'LL SEE YOU THURSDAY.
I LOVE THE BEER INDUSTRY, AND
SOMEHOW IT'S BEEN IN MY BLOOD.
YOU KNOW, I'M CO-FOUNDER OF
SAM ADAMS, AND I WAS WORKING
WITH JIM KOCH, THE FOUNDER OF
THE BOSTON BEER COMPANY.
&gt;&gt; WHEN I THOUGHTABOUT STARTING
THE COMPANY, I THOUGHT, "WELL, I
KNOW BREWING, BUT I DON'T KNOW
BARS.
I NEED SOMEBODY WHO KNOWS BARS."
AND A BAR WAS RHONDA'S NATURAL
HABITAT.
SHE WAS TOTALLY COMFORTABLE,
COULD LIGHT UP A BAR.
BARTENDERS LOVED HER 'CAUSE
SHE'D BEEN A BARTENDER HERSELF.
&gt;&gt; MY COLOMBIAN FRIEND.
SMOOTH, EASY TO DRINK.
&gt;&gt; THAT IS NICE.
&gt;&gt; IT'S REALLY THE ULTIMATE
PARTY BEER.
IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT, I'LL BUY
YOU WHAT YOU DRINK, BUT I THINK
YOU'RE GONNA LIKE IT.
LITERALLY, I SPEND FOUR OR FIVE
NIGHTS A WEEK INSIDE BARS.
&gt;&gt; HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
&gt;&gt; TAKING A LITTLE MOONSHOT.
HERE, YOU CAN PUT ONE AROUND
EACH WHATEVER.
&gt;&gt; EACH NOSTRIL?
&gt;&gt; YEAH, OR ANYWHEREYOU WANT TO
PUT IT.
IT'S A TEDIOUS, DIFFICULT WAY
TO DO IT, BUT WHEN YOU'RE
UNDER-CAPITALIZED AND YOU'RE
BUILDING A SEGMENTFROM SCRATCH,
YOU NEED TO BE THERE TO REALLY
UNDERSTAND THE REACTIONS FROM
PEOPLE.
&gt;&gt; SO, IT'S A CURE FOR WHISKEY
DICK?
IS THAT WHAT IT IS?
&gt;&gt; IT'S A CURE FOR WHAT?
&gt;&gt; WHISKEY DICK.
&gt;&gt; IT'S JUST REALLYHAND-TO-HAND
COMBAT.
&gt;&gt; ARE YOU MARRIED?
&gt;&gt; OH, YEAH.
&gt;&gt; WHAT DOES YOURHUSBAND THINK ?
LIKE, IS HE COOL LIKE WITH YOU
GOING TO THE BARS AND
EVERYTHING?
&gt;&gt; WELL, WHEN HE MET ME, I WAS
IN THE BEER BUSINESS,SO THIS IS
ALL I KNOW.
&gt;&gt; OKAY.
&gt;&gt; CHEERS TO MOONSHOT.
&gt;&gt; I'M LEARNING EVERY DAY ABOUT
HOW TO SEE THE BRANDIN THIS NEW
CENTURY.
WHAT I DID 23 YEARS AT
SAM ADAMS -- IT'SVERY DIFFERENT
NOW, GIVEN 35 BREWERIES THEN,
VERSUS THE 1,400 INTHIS COUNTRY
NOW.
&gt;&gt; WE STARTED IT TOGETHER,SO WE
WENT THROUGH ALL THE TRENCH
WARFARE, THE UPS AND THE DOWNS.
BUT WE SHARED ALL THAT, YEAR
AFTER YEAR.
AT THE END, SHE CAME TO ME AND
SAID, "WELL, YOU'VE TAUGHT ME
EVERYTHING YOU KNOW AND THAT'S
GREAT, BUT NOW I'M NOT LEARNING
ANYTHING NEW.
AND I CAN'T GETPROMOTED BECAUSE
THERE'S ONLY ONE OTHER JOB FOR
ME TO MOVE INTO ANDTHAT'S YOURS
AND YOU'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE."
WHEN SHE LEFT, I FELT LIKE SHE
WAS READY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU MISS HER?
&gt;&gt; OH, SURE.
&gt;&gt; I FIRMLY BELIEVE THAT THE
NEXT EVOLUTION OF THE INDUSTRY
IS INDEPENDENT.
THE BEER BUSINESS DOES NEED
INNOVATION, AND IF A CONSUMER'S
DRINKING SOMETHING OTHER THAN
THE BIG THREE, THEN THERE'S A
REASON FOR THAT.
THEY'RE TRYING TO MAKE A
STATEMENT.
MY PLAN FOR THE LAUNCH OF
MOONSHOT IS BOSTONAND NEW YORK .
SO, I'M PICKING MY SPOTS, AND
I'M GERMINATING IT -- JUST A
HANDFUL OF ACCOUNTS.
FOR NOW, WITH THIS STORE -- I
DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON WITH
TIGER BEER, BUT MAYBE WE COULD
SQUEEZE RIGHT IN THERE.
&gt;&gt; YEAH, I THINKIT'S REASONABLE
TO ASK THEM FOR ONE CASE.
&gt;&gt; YEAH, THIS ISREALLY GONNA BE
THE AREA.
[ CHUCKLES ] IMPORT?
IMPORT AGAIN.
I'D SAY IN THIS AREA, THOUGH
IT'S NOT THE FASTEST-MOVING
SECTION OF THE STORE.
WITH SHELF SPACE ANDLAWS AND - -
WE HAVE SO MANY BARRIERS TO
ENTRY.
THE BIG GUYS HAVE THE MUSCLE TO
MUSCLE US OUT IF THEY WANT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THIS IS THE REAL
BATTLEGROUND IN BEER.
80% OF ALL BEER IN AMERICA IS
SOLD IN STORES LIKE THIS --
LIQUOR STORES, SUPERMARKETS,AND
CONVENIENCE STORES.
&gt;&gt; THERE'S AN AMAZING
CAT-AND-MOUSE GAME.
YOU SEE MOREFIGHTING FOR SPACE.
AND LOOK AT THE PACKAGES THAT
THEY HAVE.
THE MORE PACKAGES THEY HAVE,THE
MORE ROOM YOU NEED FOR THEM.
THIS IS A 20-PACK.
HERE'S A 12-PACK.
HERE'S A 6-PACK.
HERE'S 6-PACK CANS VERSUS
BOTTLES...
LITTLE CANS, BIGGER CANS.
&gt;&gt; IS THERE REALLY A NEED FOR A
BUD ICE 12-PACK NEXT TO A BUD
ICE 6-PACK NEXT TO A BUD ICE
6-PACK?
PROBABLY NOT, BUT IT MEANS THAT
THEY'VE GOT THIS BILLBOARD
EFFECT AND THEY HAVE A MUCH
BETTER BRAND RECOGNITION.
&gt;&gt; IT'S SIMILAR TO WHAT I CALL
THE CEREAL BOARD.
YOU KNOW, GENERALMILLS MAY COME
OUT WITH 50 DIFFERENT CEREALS.
PART OF THE REASONWHY THEY HAVE
50 CEREALS IS NOT JUST BECAUSE
THEY THINK THEY'RE ALL SELLING
WELL, BUT BECAUSE THOSE 50
CEREALS WILL TAKE UP MORE SPACE
ON THE SHELVES AND AT THE
EXPENSE OF ONE OF THE RIVALS.
&gt;&gt; IT IS A JUNGLE IN THE
SUPERMARKET.
IF YOU THINK ABOUT THE
ENVIRONMENT OF A SUPERMARKET,
WHERE THERE'S FINITE SHELF
SPACE, THAT IS THE BATTLE FOR A
BEER COMPANY LIKE OURSELF TO
BRING IN NEW PRODUCTS.
WHERE DO YOU GET THE SPACE?
WELL, GENERALLY, YOU TRY TO GET
IT FROM A COMPETITOR.
&gt;&gt; NO DEAL, AL.
I CAN'T MOVE ANYBODYOUT TO MOVE
YOU IN.
&gt;&gt; IF I WORK IT OUT, IS THAT
OKAY?
&gt;&gt; WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
&gt;&gt; ATTABOY!
&gt;&gt; REAL BEER TASTE.
SAY, "HELLO, MELLOW JAX."
[ BOTTLES BREAKING ]
&gt;&gt; HEY, B.B., BRING THAT BUSCH
BAVARIAN INTO THIS BIG EMPTY
SPACE.
SOMETIMES YOU HAVE TO USE A
DIFFERENT APPROACH.
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: IN 2005,
ANHEUSER-BUSCH INTRODUCED
BUDWEISER SELECT.
&gt;&gt; SO, WHAT'S DIFFERENT ABOUT
BUDWEISER SELECT?
GOOD QUESTION.
&gt;&gt; AND HERE WE HAVE DUFF, DUFF
LITE, AND OUR NEWEST FLAVOR,
DUFF DRY.
WHAT DOES THE FUTURE HOLD FOR
DUFF?
[ CHUCKLES ]
LET'S JUST SAY WE'VE GOT A FEW
IDEAS UP OUR SLEEVE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: EVEN THOUGH IT'S HARD
TO KNOW WHAT'S DIFFERENT ABOUT
BUDWEISER SELECT,ANHEUSER-BUSCH
WAS ABLE TO PLACE IT AT EVERY
STORE IN AMERICA ALMOST
OVERNIGHT BY FINDING WAYS TO
REPLACE THEIR COMPETITORS'
BEERS.
BUDWEISER SELECT WAS ONLY THE
LATEST ENTRY INTO
ANHEUSER-BUSCH'S STABLE OF
BRANDS, SOME FAMILIAR...
SOME NOT SO MUCH.
&gt;&gt; BOTTOM LINE IS -- IF A BIG
PLAYER WANTS TO GET SOME SHELF
SPACE, THEY'RE GONNA GET IT.
RETAILERS USE ALLSORTS OF FANCY
SOFTWARE AND FIGURE OUT HOW TO
FIT EVERYTHING INTO THE FIXED
SPACE.
A PLANOGRAM IS SIMPLY A
TWO-DIMENSIONAL IMAGE OF WHAT A
SET OF GROCERY SHELVES LOOK
LIKE.
&gt;&gt; YOU KNOW, IT'S ONE THING TO
HAVE A STORE ORDER YOUR BEER,
AND IT'S ANOTHER THING TO HAVE
IT DISPLAYED IN A MANNER WHERE
IT'S ACTUALLY GONNA BE SEEN.
&gt;&gt; WE DID A HUGE STUDY.
THE FACT IS -- GUESSWHAT'S MOST
IMPORTANT.
EYE LEVEL.
&gt;&gt; WELL, EVERYONEWILL TELL YOU ,
FIRST POSITION -- EYE LEVEL.
OKAY, I WALK INTO THE BODEGA,
AND I'M LOOKING ATMY SELECTIONS
OF BEER.
EYE LEVEL, AT THE HAND, FIRST
CHOICE.
&gt;&gt; SHELF SPACE IS REAL ESTATE,
AND RETAILERS HAVETO DECIDE HOW
TO ALLOCATE THAT REAL ESTATE.
A CATEGORY CAPTAIN IS CHOSEN IN
A CATEGORY.
IT'S USUALLY THE LEADING BRAND.
BY VIRTUE OF BEING A BETTER
FRIEND TO THE RETAILER,THEY GET
THE BREAKS.
WHO DO YOU THINK KNOWS MORE
ABOUT BEER -- THE BIG GROCERY
CHAIN, LIKE, LET'S SAY,
KROGER'S, OR ANHEUSER-BUSCH?
FRANKLY, IT'S OBVIOUS, RIGHT?
ANHEUSER-BUSCH SPENDS ALL THEIR
TIME ON BEER.
KROGER DOESN'T SPEND VERY MUCH
TIME AT ALL.
THEY GOT 350 OTHER CATEGORIES.
&gt;&gt; OF COURSE, EACH SET CAPTAIN
IS GOING TO, IN LARGE MEASURE,
LOOK OUT FOR THEIR BRANDS AND
PERHAPS EVEN NOT LOOK OUT
SPECIFICALLY FOR OTHER PEOPLE'S
BRANDS.
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF A SET
CAPTAIN WHO DOESN'TWORK FOR ONE
OF THE BIG THREE.
TYPICALLY, THE SETCAPTAIN WORKS
FOR ANHEUSER-BUSCH.
&gt;&gt; AND OF COURSE,THE BIGGER YOU
ARE, THE MORE POWER YOU HAVE,
AND THEY TEND TOLISTEN TO THESE
PEOPLE AND LET THEMDECIDE WHERE
TO PLACE THE BEER, EVEN THOUGH
IT'S NOT THEIR STORE.
&gt;&gt; THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT HAS
LOOKED INTO THIS.
TO MY KNOWLEDGE,THERE'S BEEN NO
ANTITRUST TYPE OF ACTION
CURRENTLY TAKEN.
I MEAN, IT'S ON THE MARGIN.
&gt;&gt; YOU KNOW, THE BIG GUYS
CONTROL THE SHELF SPACE.
WE DON'T.
THE BIG BREWERS SITTHERE AROUND
THE TABLE WITH THEIR
REPRESENTATIVES DOING THE
SCHEMATIC.
WE'RE NOT AT THE TABLE.
[ HORNS HONKING ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: SAM WAS A LONG WAY
FROM HOMETOWN DELAWARE,DEBUTING
HIS LATEST BEERS TO A BIG-CITY
CROWD.
&gt;&gt; HEY, ANAT.
&gt;&gt; HEY, SAM.
&gt;&gt; HOW YOU BEEN?
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
&gt;&gt; Baron: GOOD TO SEE YOU.
&gt;&gt; COME ON IN.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU.
&gt;&gt; PARTY IN ROOM 937.
THIS IS ONE OF THEBEERS THAT'LL
BE FEATURED IN THE DINNER
TONIGHT.
THIS IS LIKE THE THIRD DINNER
THAT WE'VE DONE WITH THE
WALDORF, AND THEY'RE NOT LIKE
HYPOCRITES.
SOME PLACES WHERE YOU DO A BEER
DINNER KIND PAY LIP SERVICE TO
THEIR BEER MENU AND THEN, AFTER
THE EVENT, WALK AWAY.
BUT THESE GUYS ARE REALLY COOL.
THEY KEEP GOOD BEERS ON TAP AND
IN BOTTLES YEAR-ROUND.
EXCUSE ME. I'M SORRY.
HOW DO I GET TO OSCAR'S?
&gt;&gt; OSCAR'S, SIR -- STRAIGHT
THROUGH THE CENTER, DOWN THE
ESCALATOR, LEFT-HAND SIDE.
&gt;&gt; ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
WHEN YOU GET YOUR NEXT COURSE,
YOU'LL SEE THAT THIS BEER DOES
GREAT WITH MEAT.
A GREAT TEST TO TRY AT HOME --
LET A CAN OF COORS OR BUD OR
MOTOR OIL WARM UP TO ROOM
TEMPERATURE, PUT IT NEXT TO A
BOTTLE OF DOGFISH HEAD'S INDIAN
BROWN ALE OR SIERRA NEVADA'S
PALE ALE, AND YOU'LLNOTICE THAT
WHEN A BEER IS DRUNK AT ROOM
TEMPERATURE -- I.E., A
TEMPERATURE THAT YOU CAN TASTE
EVERYTHING IN THAT BEER --
THERE'S NO COMPARISON BETWEEN A
BEER BREWED WITH CHEAP ADJUNCTS
AND ONE THAT'S BREWED WITH ALL
BARLEY.
&gt;&gt; THE BEER HAS A CERTAIN
CHOCOLATE QUALITY TO IT.
&gt;&gt; SEE, I FEEL LIKEI'M DRINKING
ICED COFFEE.
&gt;&gt; THE DIFFERENCE IS THE
INGREDIENTS USED.
THE SMALL BREWERIES -- THEY'RE
ADDING SPECIAL INGREDIENTS TO
ENHANCE THE FLAVOR, WHEREAS THE
BIG BREWERIES ARE ADDING CORN
AND RICE TO NEUTER THE FLAVOR,
TO MAKE IT LIGHTER.
IF SOMEBODY ASKS ME,DO I WANT A
BUDWEISER...
&gt;&gt; YEAH, YOU PUNCH THEM.
&gt;&gt; ...I TELL THEM TOPUT IT BACK
IN THE HORSE.
&gt;&gt; [ Laughing ] HEY!
FRONT SIDE, BACK SIDE?
IT'S SO COOL TO SEE YOU GUYS
MAKING DECISIONS AT YOUR TABLE.
DON'T LISTEN TO YOURTELEVISION .
YOUR TELEVISION AND THE STUPID
ADS ON YOUR TELEVISION DON'T
KNOW WHAT YOU LIKE.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU LIKE.
YOU DECIDED WHAT TO DRINK FOR
YOURSELVES.
SO, CHEERS, AND THANK YOU GUYS
FOR COMING OUT TONIGHT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ UP-TEMPO VIOLIN MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ DOG BARKS ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: 2,500 MILES AWAY, IT
WAS SUPER BOWL SUNDAY IN
SANTA MONICA, CALIFORNIA.
AND WHAT'S MORE AMERICAN THAN
BEER AND FOOTBALL?
&gt;&gt; WELL, IT'S SUPERBOWL SUNDAY .
COME ON.
YOU GOT TO HAVE A BEER ON
SUPER BOWL SUNDAY.
&gt;&gt; I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO THE
BEER ADS MORE THAN ANYTHING
ELSE.
&gt;&gt; I THINK THAT'S MY FAVORITE
PART OF THE SUPER BOWL, IS THE
COMMERCIALS,ESPECIALLY THE BEER
COMMERCIALS 'CAUSE THEY'RE
ALWAYS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
&gt;&gt; DRINKING SOME BEERS AND THEN
WATCHING SOME COMMERCIALS.
&gt;&gt; THEY'RE MORE FUN AND MORE
INTERESTING THAN THE GAME IS.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHY DO YOU THINK BEER
AND SPORTS GO TOGETHER SO WELL?
&gt;&gt; ADVERTISING.
IT'S A BIG CAMPAIGN BY THE MAN.
THEY'RE TRYING TO SELL US BEER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU KNOW WHO THE
SPONSOR OF THE SUPER BOWL IS
TODAY, THE BEER SPONSOR?
&gt;&gt; I'M GONNA SAY BUDWEISER.
&gt;&gt; I'M GONNA STAY WITH
BUDWEISER.
&gt;&gt; IT'S GOT TO BE BUDWEISER
'CAUSE I'M THINKING OF THE BUD
BOWL.
&gt;&gt; BUD LIGHT!
&gt;&gt; HE'S LOOKING FOR DAYLIGHT.
&gt;&gt; WELL, THEY GOT THE FROGS.
[ FROG CROAKS ]
&gt;&gt; BUDWEISER?
&gt;&gt; I THINK BUDWEISER IS USUALLY
THE MAIN SPONSOR.
&gt;&gt; Baron: I'M SURE THAT WOULD
COME AS A TOTAL SURPRISE TO THE
FOLKS AT COORS, WHO SHELL OUT
HALF A BILLION DOLLARS TO
SPONSOR THE NFL.
SO, WHAT DID YOU GUYS THINK OF
THAT BUD LIGHT AD?
&gt;&gt; I LIKED THE BUD LIGHT
COMMERCIAL.
&gt;&gt; I LIKE IT. IT'S FUNNY.
&gt;&gt; I LIKED THE BUD LIGHT ADS.
THEY WERE PRETTY GOOD.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY
ADS ANHEUSER-BUSCH HAS IN THE
GAME TODAY?
WOULD IT SURPRISE YOU IF I TOLD
YOU THEY HAD 10 ADS,THE BIGGEST
ADVERTISER AT $26 MILLION?
&gt;&gt; IT WOULD NOT SURPRISE ME AT
ALL.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BECAUSE?
&gt;&gt; BECAUSE THEY MUST HAVE TO
ADVERTISE A LOT TO SELL A BEER
THAT TASTES THAT BADLY.
&gt;&gt; WHAT BEER DID YOU POUR THE
MOST OF TODAY?
&gt;&gt; PROBABLY BUD LIGHT, MOSTLY.
&gt;&gt; DID YOU NOTICE, AFTER THERE
WAS A CLEVER BUD COMMERCIAL, IF
ANYONE BOUGHT MORE BUD.
&gt;&gt; WE DID SELL A LOT OF BUD.
&gt;&gt; A LOT OF BUD.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BUT IT'S NOT JUST
ABOUT ADVERTISING.
FROM MOVIES...
&gt;&gt; [ BURPS ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: ...TO TV...
&gt;&gt; I LIKE BEING THE SPOKESMAN
FOR BUDWEISER 'CAUSETHEY'RE THE
NUMBER-ONE COMPANY IN SPORTS
MARKETING.
&gt;&gt; Baron: ...TO EVERY SPORT
KNOWN TO MAN...
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
&gt;&gt; SCISSORS BEATS...
&gt;&gt; Baron: ...EVEN ROCK, PAPER,
SCISSORS, ANHEUSER-BUSCH SPENDS
$300 MILLION A YEAR ON
SPONSORSHIPS, MORE THAN ANY
OTHER FORTUNE 500 COMPANY.
THEY EVEN SPONSOR THE
PRESIDENTIAL DEBATES.
&gt;&gt; WELL, CERTAINLYWE LIKE BEING
PART OF AMERICA'S PASTIMES, AND
WHEN IT COMES TO THE POLITICAL
SEASON, THE DEBATESARE RIGHT AT
THE FOREFRONT, RIGHT THERE WITH
BASEBALL AND EVERY OTHER SPORT
THAT PEOPLE ARE AVIDLY WATCHING
RIGHT NOW.
&gt;&gt; YOU KNOW, AMERICANS ARE A
FUN-LOVING NATION, AND YOU CAN
REST ASSURED THAT ONE OF THE
FEATURE ATTRACTIONS WHEREVER
LARGE CROWDS GATHER...
[ FANFARE PLAYING ]
...ARE THE WORLD-FAMOUS
CLYDESDALES, WHO HAVE
CONTRIBUTED MUCH TO MAKING THE
NAME OF ANHEUSER-BUSCH A BYWORD
AMONG THE PEOPLE OF AMERICA.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THOSE CLYDESDALES --
THEY SURE GET AROUND.
&gt;&gt; THE 2000-POUND, WORLD-FAMOUS
CLYDESDALES REPRESENT THE STATE
OF MISSOURI AND A PIECE OF
UNIQUELY AMERICAN HISTORY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: FAR FROM THE CLOMPING
OF THE CLYDESDALES HOOVES,
AMERICA'S SMALL BREWERS GATHER
EACH YEAR IN DENVER, COLORADO,
FOR THE GREAT AMERICAN BEER
FESTIVAL.
THOUSANDS OF BEER LOVERS TASTE
NEW BEERS AND MEET THE BREWERS
WHO MAKE THEM.
[ HORN BLOWING ]
&gt;&gt; WHAT BETTER PLACE TO BE THAN
THE GREAT AMERICAN BEER
FESTIVAL?
&gt;&gt; 1,700 BEERS.
&gt;&gt; THERE ARE A LOTOF BEERS HERE
YOU CAN ONLY GET IN THE CITIES
WHERE THEY'RE MADE.
YET THEY COME TO THE FESTIVAL,
LIKE PIZZA PORT ORRUSSIAN RIVER
OR DOGFISH HEAD.
&gt;&gt; I THINK AT THE END OF THE
DAY, PEOPLE WANT TO BE
RECOGNIZED AS INDIVIDUALS.
THEY DON'T WANT TO BE TOLD WHAT
THEY SHOULD DRINK.
THEY WANT TO DISCOVER FOR
THEMSELVES WHAT THEY WANT TO
DRINK.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ALL
CELEBRATING IN THAT ROOM, YOU
KNOW?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ CROWD OHHs! ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT DO YOU THINK'S
GOING ON?
I MEAN, IS BEER IN DECLINE IN
THE UNITED STATES RIGHT NOW?
&gt;&gt; NO, BEER IS NOT IN DECLINE.
I THINK MAYBE LIGHT BEER --
MEANING BEER WITH NO FLAVOR,
MASS-MARKETED BEER -- IS ON
DECLINE.
&gt;&gt; YOU KNOW, PEOPLE WANT MORE
FLAVOR.
AND THIS PART OF THE BEER
CULTURE IS THE ONLY PART THAT'S
GROWING.
&gt;&gt; YOU'RE GETTING 30,000 PEOPLE
TO COME OUT TO TRY BEER.
THIS ISN'T A SPEEDBOAT RACE.
THIS ISN'T A FOOTBALL EVENT.
&gt;&gt; THIS RENAISSANCEOF GOOD BEER
HASN'T BEEN DRIVENBY A BUNCH OF
SUITS ON MADISON AVE OR
WALL STREET.
IT'S TRULY CONSUMER-BASED.
&gt;&gt; AND THE THING IS THAT MOST
AMERICANS HAVE NEVER ACTUALLY
HAD REAL BEER.
THEY'VE HAD THE MASS-MARKET
VERSION, WHICH IS LIKE THE
MASS-MARKET VERSION OF BREAD.
YOU KNOW, IT STAYS FRESH IN A
BAG FOR TWO WEEKS?
NOT REALLY BREAD.
&gt;&gt; THEY WANT TO KNOW THE PEOPLE
THAT ARE MAKING THE BEER.
THEY WANT TO KNOW WHAT'S IN THE
BEER.
THEY WANT PASSION INTHEIR BEER.
THEY WANT FLAVOR.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT IN THE WORLD IS
THAT?
&gt;&gt; IT'S AN -- IT'S AN
ORGANOLEPTIC HOP TRANSDUCER.
IT'S CALLED RANDALL THE ENAMEL
ANIMAL.
IT'S NAMED BECAUSE WHEN YOU
DRINK A REALLY HOPPY BEER, IT
KIND OF FEELS LIKE IT'S RIPPING
THE ENAMEL OFF YOUR TEETH.
BASICALLY, THE BEERRUNS THROUGH
THE FRESH HOPS.
THE ALCOHOL IN THE BEER ACTS AS
A SOLVENT AND STRIPS THE OILS
OUT OF THE HOPS ANDPUTS THE HOP
OILS INTO YOUR GLASS.
SO, IT MAKES FOR A REALLY
INTENSE, HOPPY BEER.
MOST OF THE GUYS IN THIS ROOM
ARE A BUNCH OF FREAKY, RADICAL
FOLK ARTISTS, YOU KNOW.
AND THEY'RE TRYING TO DO
SOMETHING THAT'S OUTSIDE THE
STATUS QUO.
&gt;&gt; AND WE ACTUALLYTAKE THE WORT
AND DUMP IT RIGHT OVER THE TOP
OF THE HOPS.
&gt;&gt; WE KIND OF FORMED OUR OWN
LITTLE ALTERNATIVE PRODUCERS,
ALTERNATIVE DISTRIBUTORS, AND
ALTERNATIVE CONSUMERS.
AND WE'VE HOISTED EACH OTHER UP
INTO THE BIG OLD TROJAN HORSE
AND RODE IT INTO THE GATES AND
TOOK OUT A CAN OF WHOOP-ASS AND
WENT FROM THERE, YOU KNOW?
[ RECORD SCRATCHES ]
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT'S ANHEUSER-BUSCH
DOING HERE WITH SAM AND THE
OTHER SMALL BREWERS?
&gt;&gt; CRAFT BREWERS ALLPRETTY MUCH
ABIDE BY THE CODE OF, YOU KNOW,
"INDIVIDUAL, AND CELEBRATE BEER
AND CELEBRATE THE MOMENT."
THERE'S A LOT WE CAN LEARN, AS
BIGGER BREWERS, ABOUT THAT.
&gt;&gt; IS THERE ANYFRESH FRUIT USED
IN THIS, OR IS IT ALL EXTRACT?
&gt;&gt; IT'S ALL -- IT'S ALL -- IT'S
ALL EXTRACTS.
&gt;&gt; EVERYTHING THATTHEY'RE DOING
TO ME REEKS OF IDENTITY THEFT,
THE IDENTITY THEFT OF THE TRUE
CRAFT BREWERS.
THERE'S SOME PRETTY DUBIOUS
STUFF GOING ON UNDER THEIR
CONTROL
SO, I'M PRETTY WARY OF THEIR
INTENTIONS.
&gt;&gt; WELL, AS A BREWMASTER,I HAVE
WHAT YOU MIGHT CALLTHE GREATEST
JOB IN THE WORLD BECAUSE I GET
TO MAKE BEER AND TO WORK FOR A
COMPANY LIKEANHEUSER-BUSCH THAT
IS AS PASSIONATE ABOUT MAKING
BEER AS I AM.
&gt;&gt; ANHEUSER-BUSCH ISDOING LIKE,
YOU KNOW, PUMPKIN ALE THIS AND
DA-DA-DA THAT.
I DON'T WANT TO SEE A SIX-PACK
OF $3.99 ANHEUSER-BUSCH PUMPKIN
BEER NEXT TO MY $7.99 FOUR-PACK
OF PUMPKIN BEER.
I KNOW WHAT IT TOOK TO GET US
INTO THAT BOTTLE.
&gt;&gt; CRAFT BEERS HAVE BEEN DOING
WELL LATELY IN THE MARKET, AND
SO WE'RE BREWING BEERS THAT ARE
COMPARABLE IN TASTE, PROFILE,
AND APPEARANCE WITH THEIRS.
A BEER LIKE PUMPKIN SPICE WOULD
HAVE SOME SPICES IN IT AND,JUST
LIKE WHEN YOU COOK ON THE STOVE
AT HOME, YOU HAD A LITTLE MORE
OF THIS AND A LITTLE MORE OF
THAT UNTIL YOU GET IT THE WAY
YOU LIKE IT.
&gt;&gt; TO THE UNINITIATED CONSUMER,
HE GOES UP TO THAT DOOR --
"WELL, I'M NOT GONNA RISK EIGHT
BUCKS, BUT I'LL RISK FOUR
BUCKS."
AND THEN, IF THAT PRODUCT ISN'T
MADE WITH THE CARE THAT THE
SMALL BREWERIES MAKE IT WITH,IT
MIGHT TURN THAT CONSUMER OFF
FROM EVER WANDERING TO THAT
CRAFT SEGMENT OF THE STORE
AGAIN.
&gt;&gt; I'M PART OF A TEAM FULLY
ASSIGNED TO INNOVATEAND TO COME
UP WITH NEW PRODUCTS AND TO BE
OUT IN THE MARKETAND LOOKING AT
WHAT PEOPLE ARE DRINKING AND
WHAT THEY'RE AFTER TODAY IN A
BEER.
SO, THE POPULARITY OF ORGANIC
FRUIT PRODUCTS IS ON THE RISE.
ORGANIC BEERS ARERELATIVELY NEW
ON THE SCENE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: HERE'S A COMPANY THAT
SEEMS TO BE GETTING IN ON THE
ORGANIC BOOM -- GREEN VALLEY
BREWING, FAIRFIELD, CALIFORNIA.
[ HORN HONKING ]
[ HORNS HONKING ]
CAN I ASK YOU A QUESTION?
&gt;&gt; SURE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU KNOW WHERE THE
GREEN VALLEY BREWINGCOMPANY IS ?
&gt;&gt; I'VE NEVER HEARD OF IT.
&gt;&gt; I KNOW WHEREGREEN VALLEY IS,
BUT NOT THE GREENVALLEY BREWING
COMPANY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IS THERE ANOTHER
BREWERY IN THIS TOWN?
&gt;&gt; OH, YES.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHAT BREWERY IS IT?
&gt;&gt; BUDWEISER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BUDWEISER.
&gt;&gt; ANHEUSER-BUSCH.
&gt;&gt; BUDWEISER -- THAT'S THE ONLY
BREWERY I KNOW OF, AND THAT'S
NOT LIKE A MICROBREWERY, WHICH
SOUNDS LIKE WHATYOU'RE SPEAKING
OF.
&gt;&gt; Baron: MM-HMM.
WILD HOP -- IT'S AN ORGANIC
BEER.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF IT?
&gt;&gt; NO.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IT'S LIKE AN ORGANIC
BEER, AND IT SAYS ON IT
"GREEN VALLEY BREWING."
&gt;&gt; NO. I'M A BUD MAN.
&gt;&gt; THAT SOUNDS LIKE A
MICROBREWERY TO ME BECAUSE IT'S
NOT SOMETHING LARGE AND
CONGLOMERATE LIKE
ANHEUSER-BUSCH.
&gt;&gt; THAT IS THE ANHEUSER-BUSCH
BREWERY RIGHT OUT HERE,
ABSOLUTELY.
&gt;&gt; I BELIEVE THEY'RE OUT THAT
WAY.
&gt;&gt; AND YOU CAN GETON HIGHWAY 12
AND GET TO BOTH JELLY BELLY AND
BUDWEISER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: MAYBE IT'SBEHIND THAT
BANK.
THIS IS THE GREENVALLEY BREWING
COMPANY?
NO WONDER ANHEUSER-BUSCH DOESN'T
PUT ITS NAME ON THE LABEL.
&gt;&gt; LET'S POUR OURSELVES A
WILD HOP HERE.
WE PROVIDE ORGANICBEERS FOR OUR
BEER DRINKERS BECAUSE THEY TOLD
US THAT THAT WAS IMPORTANT TO
THEM AND WE WANTED TO BE THERE
WITH AN ORGANIC BEER THAT WE
THOUGHT HAD ANHEUSER-BUSCH
ATTRIBUTES OF CRAFTSMANSHIP AND
QUALITY.
THE COOL PART IS I GET TO TASTE
THEM ALL.
SO, MY INVOLVEMENT IS PART OF A
BIGGER GROUP THAT DEVELOPS
PRODUCTS AND THEN DETERMINES
WHICH ONES ARE GOOD ENOUGH TO
HAVE THE ANHEUSER-BUSCH NAME ON
THEM.
&gt;&gt; IF YOU'RE A SMALL BREWER,YOU
SHOULD BE CONCERNED ABOUT
ANHEUSER-BUSCH BECAUSE THEY'RE
GONNA GO AFTER EVERY SINGLE
NICHE, EVERY SINGLE OPPORTUNITY
THEY CAN FIND.
AND IF THEY HAVE TO HAMMER AWAY
AT SOME LOCAL BREWER'S SHARE OF
A MARKET IN PEORIA, ILLINOIS,
WELL, THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE GONNA
DO.
&gt;&gt; I REMEMBER DISTINCTLY THAT I
LITERALLY WAS IN THE SHOWER IN
THE MORNING, AND STREAMING ON
ABC "GOOD MORNING" WHATEVER IT
IS, "ANHEUSER-BUSCH TO LAUNCH A
BEER WITH CAFFEINE."
A CATEGORY KILLER IS A BRAND
THAT IS CREATED TO LITERALLY
KILL THE COMPETITION.
MY INITIAL THOUGHT WAS,"THEY'RE
JUST GONNA CRUSH ME."
THEY WENT FOR IDEAS TO REALLY
GAIN TRACTION, AND THEN THEY
COME IN AND FORCE YOU OUT.
THEY WANT A PIECE OF IT.
THEY WANT A PIECE OFEVERYTHING.
I'VE BEEN WORKING ON A
REPEATABLE MODEL THAT I CAN USE
TO EXPAND INTO OTHER MARKETS.
RAISING THE MONEY IS THE HARD
PART.
THERE IS NOT A DAY THAT I DON'T
MAKE INTRODUCTIONSOF MYSELF AND
MY COMPANY TO POTENTIAL
INVESTORS.
THEIR ISSUE IS THEY LOOK AT THE
GIANTS, THEY LOOK AT THE
BEHEMOTHS AND SAY, "HOW ARE YOU
GOING TO COMPETE WITH THEM?"
&gt;&gt; I THINK...
&gt;&gt; MY KIDS ARE 10, 8, AND 5.
AND ALL OF THEM WERE BORN INTO
THE BEER BUSINESS.
I THINK THE EXAMPLE'S GREAT,
THAT YOU CAN -- YOU CAN BE
ANYTHING YOU WANT TO BE.
&gt;&gt; YAY!
&gt;&gt; WE BOUGHT THIS HOUSE WHILE
SHE WAS STILL WITH BOSTON BEER.
I RENOVATED IT WITH A WHOLE
CREW, AND SO WE GOTA GREAT DEAL
ON THE HOUSE.
BUT EVERYTHING ELSE --
EVERYTHING'S ON THE LINE.
IT'S -- IT'S, YOU KNOW, SINK ORSWIM.
IF THIS FAILS, WE WON'T HAVE
THIS HOUSE ANYMORE.
&gt;&gt; [ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
&gt;&gt; I MEAN, THE EARLY DAYS WITH
BOSTON BEER WAS JUST SHE AND
JIM, AND SOME OF THE STUFF THAT
THEY PULLED OFF NO ONE HAD EVER
DONE BEFORE.
SHE WAS THE QUEEN OF BEER.
SHE CREATED THE BEST-RUN SALES
FORCE IN THE INDUSTRY.
EVERYBODY KNEW HER.
&gt;&gt; THERE'S ONLY ONEROOT BEER IN
THE FRIDGE, GUYS, SO SHARE IT.
&gt;&gt; I HONESTLY THOUGHT THAT ON
HER NEXT VENTURE IT WOULD HAVE
BEEN EASIER.
IT'S JUST BEEN SOFRUSTRATING TO
SEE HER COME HOME AT2:00 IN THE
MORNING AND BE UP AT7:00 AND ON
THE PHONE AND LOOKING FOR MONEY
AND HAVING TO LISTEN TO PEOPLE
WHO ARE BARTENDERS WHO ARE
TELLING HER WHAT SHE'S DOING
WRONG.
&gt;&gt; DID YOU GIVE THEM YOUR LUNCH
MONEY TODAY?
&gt;&gt; I'M LIKE, "HOW CAN YOU TAKE
THAT SHIT FROM THESE GUYS?
YOU TOOK A BEER FROMNEW ENGLAND
TO CALIFORNIA.
AND NOW HERE'S SOMEKID WHO JUST
OUT OF COLLEGE AND IS TELLING
YOU WHAT YOU DID WRONG."
BUT SHE SMILES AND AGREES AND
SAYS, "YEAH, YEAH, YEAH," AND
GETS RIGHT BACK ON.
NOTHING GETS HER DOWN.
IT'S AMAZING.
&gt;&gt; [ CRYING ]
&gt;&gt; OH, NO.
YOU KNEW I HAD TO GO OUT
TONIGHT.
&gt;&gt; UNH!
NEVER AGAIN.
&gt;&gt; WHEN YOU GET UP IN THE
MORNING, I AM GONNA BE HERE.
&gt;&gt; SO, NOW IT'S KIND OF THAT
SAME THING.
SHE'S CONSTANTLY WORKING,ON THE
ROAD, COMING IN LATE, YOU KNOW,
LIVING IT LIKE SHE ALWAYS DOES.
&gt;&gt; NO MORE TEARS.
&gt;&gt; BYE, GUYS.
&gt;&gt; NOW, LET'S TAKE A BREAK ON
THE SOCCER.
BYE.
&gt;&gt; I HAVE SEEN THEIR HANDIWORK,
PARTICULARLY WHEN THE "B"TO THE
"E" FIRST LAUNCHED IN BOSTON.
ANHEUSER-BUSCHTARGETED MOONSHOT
ACCOUNTS SPECIFICALLY, AND THE
MANAGERS THERE TOLD THAT THEY
WERE COMING IN OFFERING THEM 5
OR 10 FREE CASES TO HAVE THE
EXCLUSIVE BEER WITH CAFFEINE.
AND I-I KNOW THAT SOME PEOPLE
TOOK THE DEAL, PARTLY BECAUSE
THEY GOT TICKETS TO SOMETHING
OR -- YOU KNOW HOW THAT STUFF
WORKS.
THE BEER IS DOINGEXTREMELY WELL
IN ABOUT TWO DOZEN ACCOUNTS.
&gt;&gt; I RAN OUT.
&gt;&gt; WOW.
NEW MOONSHOT.
&gt;&gt; OOH, I LIKE THE PACKAGING.
&gt;&gt; THANK YOU.
THE LATEST AND GREATEST.
&gt;&gt; ALL RIGHT.
&gt;&gt; WE UPPED THE CAFFEINE TO
69...
&gt;&gt; YEAH. I LIKE IT.
&gt;&gt; ...AND CHANGED THE FORMULA
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
CHEERS.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
&gt;&gt; MY NAME IS GEORGE.
&gt;&gt; HOW DO YOU DO, GEORGE?
RHONDA KALLMAN.
&gt;&gt; WHERE YOU FROM?
&gt;&gt; WELL, FROM BOSTON.
&gt;&gt; OOH, I LIKE THAT.
&gt;&gt; LOOK. OOH!
THAT LOOKS AWESOME.
WOW.
&gt;&gt; WE'RE BACK TO"TRAFFICKING 24
HOURS ON THE BORDER" IN JUST A
MINUTE, BUT FIRSTTHESE BUSINESS
HEADLINES.
ROLLING ROCK, WELL, THIS BUD'S
FOR YOU.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH IS BUYING THE
BRAND POPULAR IN THE NORTHEAST
FROM A BELGIUM FIRM FOR $82
MILLION.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH ALREADY HAS...
&gt;&gt; Baron: AFTER ITS ACQUISITION
OF ROLLING ROCK, ANHEUSER-BUSCH
SHUT DOWN THE ORIGINAL BREWERY
IN LATROBE, PENNSYLVANIA, AND
MOVE ITS PRODUCTION TO THE
BUDWEISER BREWERY IN NEWARK,
NEW JERSEY.
&gt;&gt; I'M SURE LATROBE BREWERY
ISN'T THE ONLY THAT THIS
HAPPENED TO.
I MEAN, WE'RE JUST EXPERIENCING
WHAT A LOT OF OTHER COMPANIES
HAVE BEEN GOING THROUGH FOR
YEARS NOW.
&gt;&gt; IT MAY HAVE BOUGHT LATROBE'S
NAME, BUT IT'S NOT BREWED FROM
THE GLASS-LINEDTANKS OF LATROBE
ANYMORE.
&gt;&gt; THERE'S PROBABLY A LOT MORE
TO THE DEAL THAN WE KNOW ABOUT.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW THESE BIG
CORPORATIONS DO BUSINESS.
BUT, YOU KNOW, A LOT OF IT JUST
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE TO NORMAL
PEOPLE, YOU KNOW?
&gt;&gt; ANHEUSER-BUSCH BOUGHT THE
ROLLING ROCK BRAND.
THEY DIDN'T WANT THE BREWERY
ITSELF.
WHAT THEY WANTED WAS THAT BRAND
BECAUSE THEY'RE GOING AFTER THE
NOSTALGIA MARKET.
AND NOW THEY'RE GONNA START
BUYING MICROBREWERS WHO'VE BEEN
SUCCESSFUL AT ESTABLISHING
THEMSELVES AS A BRAND.
&gt;&gt; WHAT'S UP, MAN?
WE'RE IN THE MIDST OF THIS BIG
EXPANSION HERE.
WE ALREADY BIT THE BULLET AND
HAVE A BIGGER BOTTLING LINE.
SO, OUR BOTTLENECK -- NO PUN
INTENDED -- IS NOW ON THE FRONT
SIDE, OUR BREWHOUSE, AND ON THE
BACK SIDE, TANKS.
WE'RE JUMPING FROM A 50-BARREL
BREWHOUSE TO A 100-BARREL
BREWHOUSE.
IT'S GONNA BE APRETTY EXPENSIVE
PROJECT.
OF THE $9 MILLION THAT THIS
EXPANSION WILL COST US,ABOUT $6
MILLION IS GOING TO BUYING AND
REHABBING ALL THE REAL ESTATE,
AND ABOUT $3 MILLION IS GOING
INTO ALL THATBREWING EQUIPMENT.
&gt;&gt; THEY'VE COME BACK, AND
THEY'VE FOUND A WAY, WITH OUR
LIMITED ELECTRICAL HERE, TO
REDUCE THAT BOTTLENECK, POWER
THIS UP.
AND SO WE CAN MOVE IN HERE BY
JANUARY, FIRST WEEK OF JANUARY.
&gt;&gt; I FEEL AN OBLIGATION TO THE
PEOPLE I WORK WITH...
ARE YOU GUYS HAPPY WITH THE WAY
THIS SPACE...
...AND THE CUSTOMERS ULTIMATELY
WHO ARE ASKING US TO MAKE MORE
AND MORE BEER.
&gt;&gt; WE HAVE, IN THE BUDGET, A
QUARTER-MILLION DOLLARS FOR
CONCRETE WORK -- PAVERS AND
BRICK AND WALLS.
&gt;&gt; THAT'S ALL WELL AND GOOD.
DO I STILL GET THE BOCCIE
COURSE?
&gt;&gt; YES.
&gt;&gt; ALL RIGHT.
AND THAT'S A WRAP.
THIS BEER OR MINE?
WE'RE GONNA TASTE ABUNCH OF THE
AGEABLE BEERS AND JUST SEE HOW
WELL THEY'RE AGING AND SORT OF
DO A COMPARISON ON DIFFERENT
VINTAGES.
[ CORK POPS ]
OH!
&gt;&gt; HEY!
&gt;&gt; HEY.
SO, PANGAEA RECIPE
DIFFERENCES -- THIS IS A BEER
WITH ONE INGREDIENT FROM EVERY
CONTINENT.
&gt;&gt; EXTRA.
&gt;&gt; MUSTY.
&gt;&gt; THAT'D BE THERAISINS TALKING
TO YOU.
IT'S LIKE WOODINESS TO IT,ALSO.
&gt;&gt; IT'S KIND OF LEATHER-Y, KIND
OF, YOU KNOW --
&gt;&gt; I LOVE IT WHENYOU TALK ABOUT
LEATHER.
&gt;&gt; YEAH, WELL...
[ LAUGHTER ]
&gt;&gt; ALL RIGHT, SO,WHAT ARE WE ON
NEXT?
YOU KNOW, WE TAKE BEER VERY,
VERY SERIOUSLY AT DOGFISH HEAD,
BUT WE DON'T TAKEOURSELVES VERY
SERIOUSLY, YOU KNOW?
WE'RE MAKING BEER.
IT'S NOT, YOU KNOW, NUCLEAR
ARMAMENTS.
YOU WANT WHAT?
&gt;&gt; GRAPES.
&gt;&gt; GRAPES FOR BREAKFAST?
&gt;&gt; SHE SAID GRAPES.
&gt;&gt; I WANT A PANCAKE WITH SYRUP.
&gt;&gt; I'M NOT GOOD AT THAT.
MOMMY'S GOOD AT THAT.
WE'LL CHECK WHEN SHE GETS DOWN.
DO YOU WANT TO WAIT?
&gt;&gt; THE BOWLS ARE OVER HERE.
I BET SO.
&gt;&gt; I'M NOT SURE I CAN DO THAT.
MARIAH, HOW DO -- I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO MAKE A PANCAKE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MAKE A PANCAKE?
WE'RE GETTING READY TO DO THIS
EXPANSION AT THE BREWERY.
I KNOW, REGARDLESS OF WHAT THE
BANK DEAL LOOKS LIKE, THEY'RE
STILL GONNA ASK USTO PERSONALLY
SIGN FOR IT AND POTENTIALLY PUT
OUR REAL ESTATE, WHICH IS THE
RESTAURANT THAT WE OWN,
PERSONALLY UP AGAINST THAT.
SO, IN TERMS OF DOLLARS, WE'RE
GOING INTO PROBABLY MORE RISK
THAN WE EVER HAD.
&gt;&gt; THE BEER'S ALMOST DONE
BUBBLING, HUH?
SEE, SAL?
WE'RE GONNA BOTTLE THAT ON
MONDAY.
DOUG'S COMING OVER.
THERE WERE A LOT OF ANXIOUS
MONTHS AND YEARS WHERE WE OWED
PEOPLE MONEY AND HAD TO, YOU
KNOW, NOT PAY OURSELVES.
&gt;&gt; BUT I THINK THERISKS AT THAT
POINT WERE DIFFERENT 'CAUSE WE
DIDN'T HAVE ANY KIDS, WE DIDN'T
OWN A HOUSE.
WE DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING TO LOSE
EXCEPT MAYBE A CAR.
&gt;&gt; WE'LL GO TO A PARTY!
&gt;&gt; OKAY, POSSIBLY.
BUT IT'S STILL DAUNTING, AND
THERE ARE NIGHTSWHERE I WAKE UP
AT 4:00 IN THE MORNING AND I
DON'T GO BACK TO SLEEP 'CAUSE
I'M JUST THINKING ABOUT, "MY
GOD, YOU KNOW, IF -- IF WE DON'T
HIT OUR BUDGET AND IF SOMETHING
HAPPENS OR IF ONE OF THE GREAT
PEOPLE THAT HELPSOUR COMPANY BE
SO STRONG DECIDES TO LEAVE,THEN
WE HAVE TO REPLACE THEM.
OR WE COME IN TOMORROW, AND
THERE'S A DISASTER, AND
EVERYTHING'S CHANGED."
I HAVEN'T CHECKED THE YARD.
THOSE THINGS CANSOMETIMES -- I F
NOT KEEP YOU UP, THEY CAN WAKE
YOU UP."
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHILE SAM AND RHONDA
WERE GOING FURTHER INTO DEBT IN
ORDER TO GROW THEIR COMPANIES,
ANHEUSER-BUSCH JUST BOUGHT THE
RIGHTS TO GROLSCH, TIGER, AND
KIRIN BEERS.
&gt;&gt; DAILY I WILL GET A REQUEST
FROM A CONSUMER THAT WANTS TO
BUY A CASE OR TWO OR THREE.
AND I CAN'T IT TO THEM.
WE CAN'T SHIP BEER BECAUSE I
HAVE TO GO THROUGH THE
THREE-TIER SYSTEM.
&gt;&gt; Baron: SINCE THE 1930s, IT'S
BEEN ILLEGAL FORBREWERS TO SELL
BEER DIRECTLY TO CONSUMERS.
AND NOWADAYS, IT'S EVEN ILLEGAL
TO SELL IT ONLINE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
DO YOU KNOW HOW BEERGETS TO THE
STORE?
&gt;&gt; NO, HOW DOES BEER GET TO THE
&gt;&gt; PROBABLY ANAIRPLANE AND THEN
IN A TRUCK AND WHATEVER.
&gt;&gt; THEY PUT IT ON A TRUCK.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
&gt;&gt; BEERS COME ON A BUDWEISER
TRUCK TO THE STORES.
&gt;&gt; I'VE NEVER REALLY THOUGHT
ABOUT IT.
I'M SURE LIKE BARRELS AND
TRUCKS.
&gt;&gt; Baron: I WAS JUSTAS CLUELESS
WHEN I STARTED IN THE BEER
BUSINESS.
DISTRIBUTION WAS ATOTAL MYSTERY
TO ME.
&gt;&gt; THE MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DISTRIBUTE MALTBEVERAGES HAVE A
TWO-WAY RESPONSIBILITY, AND
THAT'S BECAUSE, TO THE PUBLIC,
THEY ARE THE BREWING INDUSTRY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THESE MIDDLEMEN,
CALLED WHOLESALERS OR
DISTRIBUTORS, ARE PART OF A
THREE-TIER SYSTEM ESTABLISHED
AFTER PROHIBITION TO SEPARATE
BREWERS FROM RETAILERS.
THESE THREE TIERSWERE SET UP TO
WORK A BIT LIKE THE U.S.
GOVERNMENT, EACH TIER BEING
SEPARATE BUT EQUAL, WITH NONE
HAVING CONTROL OVER THE OTHER,
OR AT LEAST THAT'S HOW THEY
PLANNED IT.
THE THREE-TIER SYSTEM IS SO
COMPLICATED THAT, WHILE I RAN
MIKE'S HARD LEMONADE,I SPOKE TO
OUR LAWYER EVERY SINGLE DAY.
&gt;&gt; ...OF INTERESTING BEER
BOTTLES AND SUCH.
&gt;&gt; Baron: OH, MY GOD.
VERY COOL.
&gt;&gt; AFTER PROHIBITION, THE
COUNTRY CAME TO A DECISION.
LETTING THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
LEGISLATE FOR THE ENTIRE
COUNTRY, IN TERMS OF TEMPERANCE
AND MORALITY OF ALCOHOL WAS A
REALLY DUMB IDEA.
AND SO THERE WAS A DELIBERATE
ATTEMPT TO GIVE MORE POWER TO
THE STATES.
BUT IF YOU'RE A SMALL BREWER,
THERE'S A HECK OF A LOT OF LAWS
TO SORT THROUGH IN THIS
INDUSTRY.
I DON'T KNOW IF THEY'RE GONNA
HOLD UP.
&gt;&gt; Baron: ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE
WHAT WE CAN DO.
WHOA!
&gt;&gt; YOU'VE GOT APATCHWORK QUILT.
THERE'S VERY LITTLE UNIFORMITY.
NOW WE GOT THROUGH WYOMING.
YOU'VE GOT A WHOLESECONDARY SET
OF REGULATIONS.
&gt;&gt; Baron: "BASIC MANDATORY
LABELING INFORMATION FOR MALT
BEVERAGES, VOLUME 3."
THAT'S 37,000 BEER LAWS?
&gt;&gt; MY GUESS IS THAT IT'S MORE
THAN 37,000 BEER LAWS.
&gt;&gt; Baron: THE BEER LAWS ARE
TEETERING.
&gt;&gt; THE BEER LAWS ARE TEETERING?
HERE, WE SHOULD JUST...
&gt;&gt; Baron: SO, DOES THE
THREE-TIER SYSTEM STILL WORK 75
YEARS LATER?
AAH!
&gt;&gt; WHOA!
&gt;&gt; Baron: IS IT STILL RELEVANT
TODAY?
&gt;&gt; ONE OF OUR BIGGEST ISSUES IS
MAKING SURE THAT WE CAN GET OUR
BEERS ONTO THE SHELVES.
IT'S OUR JOB TO MAKE SURE THOSE
BEERS SELL, BUT IF YOU CAN'T
EVEN GET IT TO THE SHELVES,
THAT'S A DIFFICULT PROPOSITION.
&gt;&gt; Baron: SO, HOW DOES IT ALL
WORK?
AND WHO ARE ALLTHESE MIDDLEMEN,
ANYWAY?
&gt;&gt; ...DAYS OF INVENTORY ARE WE
ON CORONA?
ARE WE CATCHING UP?
&gt;&gt; Baron: THAT'S SIMON BERGSON,
THE GUY ON THE RIGHT.
&gt;&gt; TOTAL WAREHOUSE RIGHT NOW IS
ABOUT...
&gt;&gt; Baron: SIMON WAS MY LARGEST
DISTRIBUTOR ATMIKE'S AND IS THE
FOURTH-LARGEST BEER DISTRIBUTOR
IN THE COUNTRY WITH OVER $600
MILLION IN SALES.
HOW DOES THIS GET INTO A BAR OR
A STORE?
&gt;&gt; THAT'S WHAT WE DO FOR A
LIVING.
WE'RE DISTRIBUTORS.
AND IT'S OUR GOAL TO GET IT
EITHER ON THE SHELFOR SERVED AT
A BAR AND TO MAKE SURE IT STAYS
FRESH.
SAL.
&gt;&gt; YES?
&gt;&gt; WE HAVE THE HEAT ON.
&gt;&gt; YES.
&gt;&gt; WHY IS THE DOOR OPEN?
&gt;&gt; THAT DOOR'S BROKE.
WE'RE WAITING FOR AREPAIRMAN TO
COME AND FIX THE MOTOR.
WE HAVE OVER A MILLION SQUARE
FEET OF WAREHOUSING, AND WE'RE
CONSTANTLY REFILLINGTHE SHELVES
FOR OUR TRUCKS WHEN WE LOAD
EVERY NIGHT.
GOOD MORNING. HOW'S EVERYTHING?
&gt;&gt; IT'S TIGHT, BUT...
&gt;&gt; DOING GOOD.
WE SELL ABOUT 11 MILLION CASES
OF CORONA AND JUST ABOUT 11
MILLION CASES OF COORS.
THEY ARE JUST ABOUT
NECK-AND-NECK IN OUR COMPANY,
VERSUS A PRODUCTLIKE SAM ADAMS,
WHICH IN THIS MARKET WILL SELL
ABOUT 600,000 CASES.
&gt;&gt; 90% OF THE BEER THAT A
DISTRIBUTOR DISTRIBUTES IS FROM
ONE OF THE LARGE COMPANIES.
OF COURSE THEY HAVE TO PAY
ATTENTION TO THE LARGE
COMPANIES, SOMETIMES TO THE
DETRIMENT TO THE OTHER 10%.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHEN THE THREE-TIER
SYSTEM WAS ESTABLISHED, POWER
WAS GIVEN TO THE STATES, WHO
THEN SPLIT THEMSELVES INTO
TERRITORIES.
SO, TODAY IN MOST STATES, THERE
ARE ONLY TWO OR THREE BIG
DISTRIBUTORS PER TERRITORY,
WHICH MEANS THAT IF YOU'RE A
SMALLER BREWER, YOU HAVE TO GET
ON ONE OF THESE TRUCKS IF YOU
WANT TO GET YOURBEER TO MARKET .
&gt;&gt; IN A LOT OF CASES, OUR
WHOLESALERS ARE THE SAME
WHOLESALERS FOR MILLER.
WHAT'S HAPPENED INCREASINGLY
OVER TIME IS THAT THE
WHOLESALERS THAT DON'T SELL
BUDWEISER, IN MANY CASES, SELL
ALL THE OTHER BRANDS.
&gt;&gt; FOR SMALL BREWERS, IF THERE
ARE TWO DISTRIBUTORS, ONE OF
WHOM WON'T CARRY ANYTHING BUT
THEIR BREWERY'SPRODUCTS AND ONE
OF WHOM HAS A VERY CROWDED
HOUSE, YOU MAY NOT BE ABLE TO
GET INTO THE MARKETPLACE.
&gt;&gt; THEANHEUSER-BUSCH NETWORK - -
THEY ARE A DIFFICULT COMPETITOR
BECAUSE THEY HAVE VERY DEEP
POCKETS AND THEY CANMAKE ALMOST
ANYTHING HAPPEN.
&gt;&gt; Baron: TODAY, 70% OF
ANHEUSER-BUSCH DISTRIBUTORS
CARRY ONLY THEIR PRODUCTS,
EFFECTIVELY SHUTTING OUT SMALL
PLAYERS.
&gt;&gt; I DON'T THINKANYBODY HAS THE
POWER OVER THEIR WHOLESALER
NETWORK THATANHEUSER-BUSCH HAS.
I MEAN, IT'S THE HEART OF YOUR
BUSINESS.
IF THE WHOLESALER'S NOT WITH
YOU, YOU CAN -- YOU CAN STAND
THERE AND BANG A BALL-PEEN
HAMMER OFF YOUR THUMB ALL YOU
WANT, AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET
ANY RESULTS.
&gt;&gt; WHEN THAT SYSTEM BEGINS TO
BREAK DOWN AND THAT MIDDLE TIER
IS NOT AS INDEPENDENT AS IT
SHOULD BE, THAT'S WHEN CRAFT
BREWERS HAVE CHALLENGES IN
GETTING THEIR BEER TO THE
CUSTOMERS.
&gt;&gt; THE THREE-TIERSYSTEM CREATES
A LEVEL PLAYING FIELD FOR ALL
BREWERS, RETAILERS, AND
CONSUMERS.
&gt;&gt; THIS SYSTEM HAS SERVED US
WELL FOR 70 YEARS.
SPRINGING FROM THE FAILURE OF
PROHIBITION, WHATHAS EMERGED IS
A VIABLE SYSTEM OF SAFEGUARDS,
STATE AND LOCAL CONTROL,ORDERLY
MARKETS, ANDTREMENDOUS CONSUMER
CHOICE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: CLEARLY, IT WORKS FOR
THE BIG BREWERS AND BEER
DISTRIBUTORS, BUT ISIT GOOD FOR
CONSUMERS?
&gt;&gt; I OFTEN LOOK AT IT IN TERMS
OF -- IT'S A CHALLENGE FOR THE
BEER DRINKER -- ACCESS TO THE
BEERS THAT THEY LIKE.
&gt;&gt; ♪ DO DO DO ♪
♪ DO DO DO ♪
&gt;&gt; SO, HERE WE ARE, THE
COUNTDOWN TILL BREW DAY.
I THINK WE GOT ABOUT TWO WEEKS.
&gt;&gt; UH-HUH.
&gt;&gt; THAT'S THE PLAN.
YOU CAN SEE THERE'STHE LAST FEW
THINGS THAT HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER.
SO, FINALLY WE GOT OUR BIG-BOY
BREWHOUSE.
LIKE BIG-BOY UNDERPANTS, WE'RE
FINALLY STRAPPING ONOUR BIG-BOY
BREWHOUSE.
RIGHT NOW, MYSELF AND -- I
KNOW -- ALL THEBREWERS ARE JUST
REALLY EXCITED TO GROW INTO A
TRUE REGIONAL BREWERY,YOU KNOW,
LIKE BEFORE PROHIBITION, WHEN
THERE WERE, YOU KNOW,DOZENS AND
DOZENS OF BREWERIES THAT WERE
OVER 100,000 BARRELS.
AND THAT -- THAT ERA, YOU KNOW,
DISAPPEARED, YOU KNOW, BECAUSE
OF THE GREATMARKETING SKILLS OF
THE MILLERS AND THEBUDS AND THE
COORS OF THE WORLD.
YOU KNOW, I'M PROUD OF THIS
100-BARREL BREWHOUSE, BUT I'M
PROUD TO SAY MYBUDDIES AT STONE
HAVE A BREWERY THIS BIG.
MY BUDDIES AT NEW BELGIUM HAVE
ONE TWO OR THREE TIMES.
THE CHALLENGE, AS YOU GROW, IS
HOW CAN YOU KEEP YOUR IDENTITY
SPECIAL, AND HOW DO YOU
DIFFERENTIATE YOURSELVES FROM A
BIGGER BREWERY ONCE YOU'RE
BREWING ON THE SALE WE'RE ABOUT
TO BREW ON?
THE GREAT THING IS I SEE ALL
THESE PEOPLE STEPPING UP.
THERE'S 100 PEOPLE AT THIS
COMPANY WHO -- YOU KNOW, THEIR
OWN JOBS ARE AT RISK IF WE DON'T
MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
THEY'RE AS AMBITIOUS AS I AM TO
SEE THIS EXPANSION WORK.
I WOULD HATE TO SEE A DAY WHEN
THE PEOPLE THAT WERE WORKING
HERE EVERY DAY NOLONGER HAD 51 %
OF THIS COMPANY, NOLONGER COULD
DECIDE TO DO WHAT WE'RE DOING
BECAUSE IF WE -- IF THAT DAY
CAME, A BEER LIKE THIS, AT $150
A CASE -- THAT'D BE THE FIRST
THING THAT WOULD GO.
I'M VERY WORRIED THAT WE'LL
OUTGROW THE LOANS THAT WE JUST
MADE.
IF WE KEPT GROWING AT 40%, 50%,
60% A YEAR, THE WAY WE HAVE
BEEN, THERE'S NO DOUBT IN MY
MIND THAT WE WOULD NEED MORE
MONEY TO EXPANDBEFORE I PAY OFF
THIS $9 MILLION WORTH OF DEBT
THAT I HAVE.
WE'RE GETTING ALL THESE CALLS
FROM VENTURE CAPITALISTS AND
SUITS FROM NEW YORK WHO ARE
LIKE, "OH, WOW, YOU GUYS ARE
KICKING ASS.
WE WANT TO TAKE YOU PUBLIC.
WE WANT TO INVEST IN YOUR
COMPANY."
BUT I DON'T WANT TO GROW AT THE
RATE THATNECESSITATES US LOSIN G
CONTROL OF THE COMPANY.
AND THAT'S WHAT I WORRY ABOUT,
IS THAT SOME OUTSIDEFORCE WOULD
BE ABLE TO, YOU KNOW, DETER US
FROM OUR LABOR OF LOVE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: HELLO!
HOW ABOUT A TAXI?
HEY!
TAXI!
&gt;&gt; I WILL HAVE TO GET BACK TO
YOU...
THE MONEY RAISING HAS PROBABLY
BEEN THE MOST FRUSTRATING PART.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT OFA CATCH-22.
THE PEOPLE WITH THE MONEY ARE
WAITING TO SEESOMETHING HAPPEN.
BUT I CAN'T MAKE IT HAPPEN
WITHOUT HAVING THE MONEY.
OKAY. THANK YOU. BYE-BYE.
[ HORNS HONKING ]
IN THE LAST 10 DAYS, I THINK
I'VE HAD 7 DIFFERENT MEETINGS
FOR RAISING MONEY.
IT'S TOO SMALL FOR MOST AND TOO
BIG OF AN IDEA FOR THE REST.
I HAVE THE BRAND.
I JUST NEED TO FIND THE PEOPLE
THAT HAVE A STOMACH FOR THIS
KIND OF INVESTMENT.
HI, THERE.
&gt;&gt; HI, THERE.
&gt;&gt; HOW ARE YOU?
&gt;&gt; NICE TO MEET YOU.
&gt;&gt; BROUGHT THE GOOD STUFF.
RHONDA KALLMAN.
&gt;&gt; HI, NICE TO MEET YOU.
&gt;&gt; NICE TO BE HERE. THANK YOU.
WHEN I CAME UP WITH THIS IDEA,
I WAS, YOU KNOW, THINKING, JUST
REALLY THINKING ABOUT WHAT
CONSUMERS WERE DOING TODAY.
AND WHEN I LOOKED AT STARBUCKS,
RED BULL -- AND THE COMMONALITY
THERE, OF COURSE, IS CAFFEINE.
AND I THOUGHT, "WELL,THERE'S AN
UNMET NEED IN BEER,"AND THAT'S,
YOU KNOW, WHAT THIS COMPANY IS
SET UP TO DO.
SO, I'M LOOKING FOR $800,000,
WHICH WOULD GET THE COMPANY TO
SUSTAIN PROFITABILITY.
&gt;&gt; BUT IS THAT HOW MUCH MONEY
YOU NEED TO BE DONE WITH THAT
OR...
&gt;&gt; WELL, NO, BUT THAT'S REALLY
JUST TO GET ME TO THE NEXT
LEVEL.
&gt;&gt; MM-HMM.
&gt;&gt; AND THEN -- I MEAN, I
DON'T --
&gt;&gt; HAVE YOU TALKED TO ANY
OTHER -- OTHER PROFESSIONAL
INVESTORS, OTHER THAN THE --
&gt;&gt; I'M DOING IT IN STAGES
BECAUSE IF I GOT TO AN ANGEL
THAT MIGHT WRITE CHECK FOR
$50,000 AND THEN SEETHAT I NEED
$6 MILLION, THEY'RE-- YOU KNOW,
IT'S TOO BIG OF A JUMP.
&gt;&gt; AT THE STAGE OF DEVELOPMENT
YOU'RE AT RIGHT NOW, IT'S
PROBABLY GONNA BE A LOT HARDER
TO GET, YOU KNOW, A TRUE
INSTITUTIONAL INVESTOR TO...
&gt;&gt; I MEAN, I THINK IT WOULD BE
GREAT TO MAKE ANINTRODUCTION TO
A COUPLE OF PEOPLE THAT DO SORT
OF THE EARLIER STAGE AND THEN
JUST SEE WHERE THAT GOES.
AND THE, YOU KNOW, I THINK WE
COME IN MORE AT THE VENTURE
STAGE -- SO, ALITTLE BIT LATER.
BUT IT'S NOT THAT FAR OFF,
NECESSARILY.
&gt;&gt; YEAH, I DON'T THINK SO.
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
&gt;&gt; EVERY DAY THAT GOES BY, I
HAVE TO MAKE A NEW DECISION OF,
"WHICH PART OF MY LIFE AM I
GOING TO MORTGAGE OR SELL?"
AND I'M DONNING MY KEDS, BUT I
THINK I'M GONNA HOLD OFF.
I'M HOPEFUL THATTHERE WILL BE A
STRATEGIC PARTNER INTHE FUTURE.
YOU KNOW, IT'S THAT SITUATION.
I'M JUST ON THE ROAD BY MYSELF.
IT'S LONELY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHEN I GOT THIS
INVITATION TO THE BEER
INDUSTRY'S ANNUAL LEGISLATIVE
CONFERENCE, I WAS THRILLED AT
THE OPPORTUNITY TOSEE DEMOCRACY
IN ACTION.
I MEAN, WHAT DO BEER AND
POLITICS HAVE TO DO WITH EACH
OTHER?
&gt;&gt; BEER CERTAINLYMAKES POLITICS
A LOT EASIER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHY THE BEER INDUSTRY NEEDS A
LOBBY?
&gt;&gt; NO, I DON'T.
&gt;&gt; SEEMS LIKE THERE'S A LOBBY
FOR EVERYTHING.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHY DO BEER PEOPLE
NEED A LOBBY?
&gt;&gt; WELL, FOR SEVERAL REASONS WE
NEED A LOBBY.
WE GO TALK TO MEMBERS ABOUT THE
ISSUES WE HAVE TODAY THAT LOOK
AT THE INTEGRITY OF OUR
THREE-TIER SYSTEM.
THIS SYSTEM MANDATES THAT YOU
CAN BE A BREWER, A WHOLESALER,
OR A RETAILER.
WE WANT CONGRESS TOREMEMBER THE
SYSTEM WORKS WELL.
WE GET ABOUT A THOUSANDS PEOPLE
IN WASHINGTON EVERY YEAR, WHICH
IS, AMONGST ALL LEGISLATIVE
CONFERENCES, CERTAINLY ONE OF
THE BIGGER ONES.
&gt;&gt; Baron: I EVENTRIED TO GET MY
OWN MEETING WITH THE
CONGRESSMAN.
STEVE, HI.
THIS IS ANAT BARON CALLING.
WE CALLED YOU YESTERDAY ABOUT
TRYING TO GET IN TO SEE
CONGRESSMAN FRANK TODAY.
ANYTIME THE BEER FOLKS GOT
TOGETHER, THERE WERE PARTIES.
&gt;&gt; HEY, IN D.C., YOU GOT TO BE
POLITICAL, RIGHT?
&gt;&gt; Baron: THAT'S RIGHT.
ARE YOU GONNA MARCH, MARCH ON
WASHINGTON?
&gt;&gt; OKAY.
WHAT, YOU WANT TOTAKE A PICTURE
OF ME AND CHUCK SCHUMER?
&gt;&gt; THOUSAND BEER DISTRIBUTORS
GOING DOWN ON CAPITOL HILL --
THEY HAVE I THINK 452 VISITS
PLANNED FOR THE SENATE AND THE
HOUSE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: AND WHAT ARE THE BIG
ISSUES THAT PEOPLE ARE GONNA
TALK ABOUT?
&gt;&gt; OH, WE'RE GONNA TALK ABOUT
THINGS THAT WE CAN DO TO SHORE
UP THE THREE-TIER SYSTEM.
&gt;&gt; Baron: SO, WHAT ARE WE
LOOKING FORWARD TO THIS WEEK?
&gt;&gt; WELL, WE'VE GOT, YOU KNOW --
OBVIOUSLY THE THREE-TIER ISSUES
ARE VERY BIG.
&gt;&gt; Baron: DO YOU THINK THAT
PEOPLE ARE WORRIED ABOUT THE
THREE-TIER SYSTEM, THE PEOPLE
HERE?
&gt;&gt; ABSOLUTELY.
EVERYBODY IS VERY CONCERNED.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IT WAS LOBBY DAY IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
THE SUN WAS SHINING.
THE BIRDS WERE CHIRPING.
THE SHOW WAS ABOUT TO BEGIN.
AS I GOT MY OWN BUTTON AND
BADGE, I COULD HEAR THE HOUSE
MAJORITY LEADER'SADDRESS TO THE
CROWD.
JOHN BEOHNER WAS SPEAKING TO
SOME OF THE VERYSAME PEOPLE WHO
HELPED PUT HIM IN OFFICE,
ESPECIALLY THIS GUY,DAVID REHR,
THEIR CHIEF LOBBYIST, WHO HEADS
THE NATIONAL BEER WHOLESALERS
ASSOCIATION.
&gt;&gt; ONE OF THE THINGS I THINK I'M
MOST PROUD ABOUT IS THAT THE
NATIONAL BEERWHOLESALERS NOW IS
RANKED AS ONE OF THE MOST
INFLUENTIAL GROUPS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
THE NBWA HAS BECOME THE
POLITICAL ARM OF THE BEER
INDUSTRY IN AMERICA.
[ APPLAUSE ]
BECAUSE THEY'RELOCATED IN EVERY
COMMUNITY, THE BEER WHOLESALERS
ARE VERY POLITICALLY INVOLVED
WITH THEIR LEGISLATORS.
AND THEY SERVE, REALLY, AS THE
EYES AND EARS OF THE BEER
INDUSTRY IN EVERY CITY AND TOWN
ALL ACROSS AMERICA.
&gt;&gt; Baron: HAVE A BEER
DISTRIBUTOR IN EVERY
CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICT?
HOW CONVENIENT WHEN YOU WANT TO
TALK TO CONGRESS.
&gt;&gt; LOBBYING IS LIKE THE FOURTH
BRANCH OF GOVERNMENT.
IT'S ABOUT POWER, IT'S ABOUT
MONEY, AND IF YOU FOLLOW THE
MONEY, THE BREWINGINDUSTRY IS A
VERY POWERFUL INDUSTRY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: IN THE 2006 ELECTION
CYCLE, POLITICAL ACTION
COMMITTEE CONTRIBUTIONS FOR THE
BEER INDUSTRY MADEIT ONE OF THE
BIGGEST GIVERS IN WASHINGTON,
BIGGER THAN GUNS AND TOBACCO
COMBINED.
&gt;&gt; THEY KNOW HOW TO MANIPULATE
CONGRESS TO GET WHAT THEY WANT.
&gt;&gt; WE WORK TOGETHER AS A VERY
COHESIVE TEAM IN PROMOTING WHAT
WE CONSIDER TO BE A PRO-BEER
AGENDA FOR THE COUNTRY.
&gt;&gt; AND WE'RE GOINGTO TALK ABOUT
THE THREE-TIER SYSTEM FOR
DISTRIBUTION, THAT WE'D LIKE TO
KEEP THAT IN PLACE.
IT'S GOOD FOR AMERICA.
&gt;&gt; THE BREWING INDUSTRY
HISTORICALLY HASBEEN VERY SMART
ABOUT HOW TO GET ACCESS IN
WASHINGTON.
&gt;&gt; WE PAY A LOT OF TAXES.
IT'S ABOUT $30 BILLION,
NATIONALLY.
IN OKLAHOMA, EXCISE TAX IS 82
CENTS A CASE, WHICH IS ABOUT --
$28 TO $30 MILLION A YEAR IS
WHAT WE PAY IN THE STATE OF
OKLAHOMA.
SO, IT'S A PRETTY GOOD CHUNK OF
CHANGE.
&gt;&gt; THE FOCUS IS TO MAINTAIN THE
CURRENT STATUS QUO OF THE THREE
TIERS IN THE BEER INDUSTRY,
WHICH IS A GAMBIT TO MAINTAIN
THE DOMINANCE OF THE LARGE
BREWERIES.
THE THREE-TIER SYSTEM WAS
ACTUALLY CREATEDSPECIFICALLY TO
BREAK UP MONOPOLIES.
INSTEAD, IT'S NOW ALLOWING THEM
TO CONTINUE.
&gt;&gt; Baron: HOW DOES THE NBWA
DECIDE WHO GETS MONEY?
WHAT TO POLITICIANS HAVE TO DO
IN RETURN?
[ BUZZER SOUNDS ]
HEY, WHY DIDN'T HE GET ANY
MONEY?
I NOTICED WHEN I WAS LOOKING AT
THE NBWA MATERIALS THAT YOU DID
ACCEPT NBWA PACK MONEY.
CAN YOU TELL ME WHY?
&gt;&gt; UM...I DON'T THINK THEY'VE
OFFERED.
&gt;&gt; Baron: YOU DON'T THINK
THEY'VE OFFERED?
WHAT'S THE BEST WAY TO MAKE IT
TO THE TOP OF ALL POLITICAL
ACTION COMMITTEES IN AMERICA?
FIND YOURSELF AN ENEMY.
[ CASH REGISTER DINGS ]
&gt;&gt; THERE ARE SOME WHO LOOK FOR
ANY OPPORTUNITY TO MAGNIFY ANY
MISTAKE AND USE IT TO SEEK
PROHIBITION OF THE MALT
BEVERAGES, WHICH ADD TO THE
ENJOYMENT OF GRACIOUS LIVING.
&gt;&gt; WE NEED TO ENSURE THAT THOSE
KIND OF NEO-PROHIBITIONIST
INFLUENCES IN AMERICA DO NOT
ATTAIN ANY OF THEIR OBJECTIVES
IN RESTRICTING THE AVAILABILITY
OF BEER FOR THE AMERICAN
CONSUMER.
&gt;&gt; Baron: NEO-PROHIBITIONISTS?
WHO ARE THEY?
I SOUGHT OUT DAVID REHR'S
ARCHENEMY, GEORGE HACKER.
ARE YOU A NEO-PROHIBITIONIST?
&gt;&gt; THE SHORT ANSWER IS, FLATLY,
NO.
I CONSUME ALCOHOL MYSELF.
DAVID REHR USES THE LABEL
"NEO-PROHIBITIONIST"AS A WAY OF
RALLYING HIS TROOPS,AS A WAY OF
GENERATING INCOME FOR HIS
ASSOCIATION, AS A WAY OF
EXAGGERATING THE THREAT.
&gt;&gt; SO, IT'S REALLY A KIND OF A
COMBINATION OF ZEALOTS, OF KIND
OF OBSESSED CONSUMERITES, ALL
JOINED TOGETHER.
&gt;&gt; IT'S MORE A TACTIC THAN A
REAL POLITICAL ARGUMENT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: I HAD TO FIND OUT IF
ANYONE ELSE HAD HEARD OF THE
SHADOWY MENACE OF
NEO-PROHIBITION.
CAN I ASK YOU GUYS A QUESTION?
I'M JUST WONDERING -- ARE YOU A
NEO-PROHIBITIONIST?
&gt;&gt; I'M SORRY?
&gt;&gt; Baron: ARE YOU A
NEO-PROHIBITIONIST, MA'AM?
&gt;&gt; NO.
&gt;&gt; Baron: NO?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT A
NEO-PROHIBITIONIST IS?
I'M LOOKING TO FIND A
NEO-PROHIBITIONIST.
DO YOU KNOW OF ANY?
I GAVE MY SEARCH FOR
NEO-PROHIBITIONISTS TO ATTEND
THE GRAND FINALE -- THE BEER
INDUSTRY'S RECEPTION FOR
AMERICA'S CONGRESSMEN AND
SENATORS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
&gt;&gt; CONGRESSMAN CURT WELDON'S
OFFICE, 7th DISTRICT OF
PENNSYLVANIA.
&gt;&gt; WEXLER, CONGRESSMAN WEXLER.
THANK YOU.
&gt;&gt; THE UGLY POLITICAL SIDE IS
THAT BIG BREWERIES INFLUENCE
POLITICS WITH LOTS OF MONEY.
IF AMERICANS ARE FED UP WITH
SPECIAL INTERESTS, THEN THEIR
BEER COMPANY SHOULDN'T BE A
SPECIAL INTEREST IN WASHINGTON,
PROMOTING PARTY POLITICS THAT
ARE NOT NECESSARILY GOOD FOR
AMERICA.
&gt;&gt; Baron: SO, ITTURNS OUT THAT ,
IN OUR DEMOCRACY, THE PEOPLE WE
ELECT DECIDE WHAT BEERS WE CAN
AND CAN'T DRINK, BASED ON
OUTDATED LAWS AND THE ALMIGHTY
DOLLAR.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
&gt;&gt; WELL, I'M NOT HERE TO LOBBY,
BUT I'M HERE TO FINDA STRATEGIC
PARTNER, AND THEY'RE ALL HERE.
THIS IS THE PLACE TO DO IT.
MOONSHOT'S PROBABLY IN 150
ACCOUNTS.
I DO HAVE A LOT OFINTEREST FROM
DISTRIBUTORS ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY.
I'M HAPPY ABOUT THAT SORT OF
PROGRESS, BUT IT'S NOT ONE OF
THOSE THINGS THATJUST TAKES OFF
OVERNIGHT.
IT NEEDS SUPPORT.
BUT I CAN ONLY BE IN SO MANY
PLACES.
THE BRAND IS HERE.
I'M REALLY SO CLOSE.
JIM ACTUALLY IS TRYING TO TRACK
ME DOWN TO HAVE COFFEE, A BEER,
LUNCH, ANYTHING.
SO, WE DID GET TOGETHER.
I WAS HOPING THAT ICOULD GET AN
INVESTMENT FROM BOSTON BEER
COMPANY AND/OR JIM.
HIS FEELING IS THAT I'M A
COMPETITOR AND IT WOULDN'T BE
ETHICAL.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME GETTING
MY HEAD AROUND THAT, BUT IF
THAT'S HOW HE WANTS TO
COMMUNICATE THE REASON, THAT'S
THE REASON HE GAVE ME.
I THOUGHT THAT COORS COULD BE A
GOOD FIT, AND PARTICULARLY I
LIKE THEIR MANAGEMENT
PERSONALLY.
IF YOU'RE GONNA DO SOMETHING,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL LIKE THE
PEOPLE THAT YOU'RE DOING IT
WITH.
FRITZ WENT ON TO SAYTHAT ALL OF
THEIR FOCUS, EFFORT,AND DOLLARS
NEED TO GET -- GO BEHIND
BUILDING THEIR COMPANY BRAND.
THEY PASSED.
I HAVE, IN FACT, APPROACHED
MILLER BREWING COMPANY, BUT I
HAVEN'T BEEN MET WITH ANY
INTEREST AT ALL, SO...
I THINK WHAT KEEPS ME UP AT
NIGHT IS NOT -- NOT BEING ABLE
TO KEEP IT GOING...FAILING.
WE HAVE $23,000 IN THE BANK
RIGHT NOW.
IT'S "OH, SHIT" MODEONCE AGAIN .
I TRACKED ANHEUSER-BUSCH DOWN.
THEY DIDN'T COME AFTER ME.
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU DO WHEN
YOU'RE IN A POSITION LIKE MINE,
IS YOU JUST HAVE TOGO AFTER IT.
YOU KNOW, I EXPECTSOMEBODY WILL
GET BACK TO ME SOONER OR LATER.
WHETHER IT'S, YOU KNOW,"WE HAVE
NO INTEREST, GOOD LUCK TO YOU,"
OR, "WE ARE INTERESTED.
TELL ME MORE."
AND I'M HOPING THAT THE LATTER
WILL HAPPEN.
GOING TO ANHEUSER-BUSCH IS LIKE
SLEEPING WITH THE ENEMY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: HI, HOW ARE YOU?
I'M JUST CHECKING TO SEE IF
AUGUST BUSCH IV HAS CHECKED IN.
THE ONE BIG GUY WHO ELUDED ME
SINCE I STARTED MAKING THE FILM
WAS AUGUST BUSCH IV.
I HAVEN'T MET AUGUST BUSCH IV.
COULD YOU INTRODUCE ME TO HIM?
AUGUST BUSCH IV?
AUGUST BUSCH IV.
&gt;&gt; WE DON'T REALLY RUN IN THE
SAME CIRCLES.
&gt;&gt; I'D BE -- HE'S A WONDERFUL
GUY.
&gt;&gt; AUGUST I KNOW IS EXTREMELY
BUSY, AND HE'S GOT A LOT ON HIS
PLATE.
&gt;&gt; HE'S HERE ALREADY.
&gt;&gt; Baron: OH, HE'S CHECKED IN?
&gt;&gt; YEAH.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WELL, HE OBVIOUSLY
WASN'T TOO BUSY TOCOME LOBBY IN
WASHINGTON.
AUGUST, HI.
MY NAME IS ANAT BARON.
HI. NICE TO MEET YOU.
I'M MAKING FILM ABOUT THE BEER
INDUSTRY, AND I'D LOVE TO GET
YOU IN IT.
I THOUGHT I'D BE BETTER OFF
TRYING TO CHARM HIM.
&gt;&gt; WOW, UM...
[ CHUCKLES ]
UM, DO YOU HAVE A CARD OR
SOMETHING?
&gt;&gt; Baron: I WOULDTAKE THAT AS A
"NO."
AFTER ALL, AUGUST ISA VERY BUSY
MAN.
HE KEEPS ADDING NEW BRANDS TO
THE ANHEUSER-BUSCH FAMILY.
IN FACT, IN THE LAST 10 YEARS,
THE COMPANY WENT FROM 26 TO 80.
I WOULDN'T LET UP.
I HAD TO UNDERSTAND WHAT WAS
BEHIND THISINSATIABLE DESIRE TO
GROW AT ALL COSTS.
DESPITE A LETTER-WRITING
CAMPAIGN, AUGUST STILL WOULDN'T
MEET WITH ME.
BUT HE DID INVITE ME TO
ST. LOUIS TO VISIT HIS KINGDOM.
AS I GOT DEEPER INTO THE CENTER
OF THE ANHEUSER-BUSCH EMPIRE,IT
FINALLY HIT ME --
ANHEUSER-BUSCH HAD GOTTEN THIS
BIG BECAUSE IT HAD POLITICIANS
AND LAWS ON ITS SIDE.
AND BY USING ITS MARKETING
MACHINE, IT WAS ABLE TO PUSH
CONSUMERS TO BUY ITS PRODUCTS,
RATHER THAN RESPOND TO MARKET
DEMAND.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH AND OTHER
CORPORATE BEHEMOTHSLIKE WALMART
AND MICROSOFT, WITH THEIR
VORACIOUS APPETITE FOR GROWTH,
SWALLOW ANYTHING AND EVERYTHING
IN THEIR PATH.
&gt;&gt; WELCOME TO 1984, AGE OF
AUTOMATION AND UNEMPLOYMENT,THE
RISE OF THE MACHINEAND THE FALL
OF MAN...
[ CHUCKLES ]
...THE END OF THE HUMAN ERA.
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHENYOU'RE A MONOPOLY
LIKE ANHEUSER-BUSCH, YOU JUST
CAN'T LET ANYTHING SLIDE.
EVERYONE'S A THREAT, NO MATTER
HOW SMALL.
&gt;&gt; THEY HAVE WEAPONS, AND WE
HAVE WEAPONS.
AND OURS MIGHT SEEM LIKE
SLINGSHOTS AND THEIR SEEMS LIKE
GIANT MISSILES, BUT OURS IS
GROUND WARFARE -- ONE CONSUMER
AT A TIME.
RECENTLY, IT'S GOTTEN A LITTLE
MORE PERSONAL.
WELL, THIS THING HERE IS
BASICALLY ANHEUSER-BUSCH
INCORPORATED AGAINST
DOGFISH HEAD.
WE'VE BEEN BREWINGCHICORY STOUT
AND PUNKIN ALE FOR PRETTY MUCH
ALMOST A DECADE, BUT SUDDENLY
WE'VE BEEN SLAPPED WITH THIS
LEGAL ACTION OF ANHEUSER-BUSCH
WANTING TO STOP US FROM USING
THOSE NAMES.
IT'D BE ONE THING IF WE WERE
CALLING IT JUST DOGFISH HEAD
STOUT OR DOGFISH HEAD
PUNKIN ALE, SPELLED OUT
"PUMPKIN."
BUT THEY'RE ACTUALLYFIGHTING TO
STOP US FROM USING THE WORK
"CHICORY" AND USING THE WORD
"PUNKIN" ON OUR LABELING.
AND I GUESS THEIR CLAIM IS THAT
THEY'RE TOO GENERIC OF TERMS.
IT MAKES YOU WONDERABOUT A BEER
LIKE NATURAL LIGHT NOT BEING A
GENERIC TERM, BUT I GUESS THEY
LOOK AT THAT A LITTLE
DIFFERENTLY.
IT'S REALLY JUST A FURTHER
EXAMPLE OF JUST HOW OPPRESSIVE
AND OBNOXIOUS THEY ARE 'CAUSE
THEY'VE GOT THE ABILITY, AND I'M
SURE THEY PLAN TO LAWYER THE
BEJESUS OUT OF US.
&gt;&gt; Baron: BUT NOT ALL
CORPORATIONS OPERATE THE SAME
WAY.
AFTER A LONG DAY AT THE COORS
CORPORATE HEADQUARTERS,
EMPLOYEES GET TOWORK OUT AT THE
COMPANY WELLNESS CENTER...
AND OF COURSE, HAVE A BEER.
AND AT MILLER, THEY CAN JUST
MEET UP AT THE EMPLOYEE PUB,
WHERE EVEN THE C.E.O. SHOWS UP
FOR A BEER AFTER WORK.
I DIDN'T SEE ANY OF THAT TEAM
SPIRIT OVER IN ST. LOUIS.
BUT IN THE END,THEY'RE ALL JUST
SELLING BEER, RIGHT?
BUT IS IT JUST ABOUT BEER?
DOES IT REALLY MATTER WHO'S
BEHIND WHAT WE DRINK, WHAT WE
EAT, WHAT WE WATCH?
WHAT HAS THE AMERICAN DREAM
BECOME?
IS IT STILL ABOUTTHE FREEDOM TO
PURSUE YOUR PASSION?
OR HAS IT BECOME ONLY ABOUT
SUCCESS AND POWER?
WHEN IS BIG BIG ENOUGH?
&gt;&gt; I DID NOT GO TO
ANHEUSER-BUSCH TO SELL OUT.
BUT GETTING THE MEETING WAS
VALIDATION THAT THE CONCEPT,THE
COMPANY, AND THE BRANDS HAVE
POTENTIAL.
I'M EVEN SEEINGBUSCH RIGHT NOW,
BELIEVE IT OR NOT.
I DID, YEAH.
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
I'M ON THE PHONE WITH MILLER,
AND MY PHONE BEEPS IN.
IT'S ANHEUSER-BUSCH.
BUT THEY PASSED FOR NOW.
TOLD THEM I'M GONNA GO PURSUE,
YOU KNOW, OTHER THINGS.
I'M SAD, REALLY, AND IT WAS ONE
OF THOSE THINGS -- "WE REALLY
WISH YOU THE BEST OF LUCK,"AND,
"KEEP IN TOUCH."
BUT THEY JUST DIDN'T WANT TO
HOLD ME UP ANY LONGER, AND
THAT'S COOL.
AT LEAST WE GOT AN ANSWER...
I WAS DISAPPOINTED.
BUT IF YOU BELIEVEIN SOMETHING,
YOU KEEP GOING.
OKAY, BYE.
OKAY.
I'LL BE HONEST WITH YOU.
THERE'S DAYS THATI'VE COME HOME
AND SAID, "I DON'T KNOW, KIDS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?"
AND THEY'RE LIKE, "KEEP GOING,
MOM."
AND MY 10-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER,
CALLIE, SAID, "WE HAVE TO KEEP
GOING 'CAUSE MY MOM'S NOT A
QUITTER."
AND I THOUGHT, "YEAH, SHE'S
RIGHT."
I HAVE 16 PEOPLE WHO HAVE
INVESTED THEIR MONEY IN THIS
AND THEIR FAITH AND THEY --
THEIR BELIEF IN ME AND THE
OPPORTUNITY, YOU KNOW?
THAT KEEPS ME GOING EVERY DAY.
I'M NOT GONNA LET THEM DOWN.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT GOING
ANYWHERE.
I'M GONNA KEEP THE COMPANY
GROWING.
I'M BUILDING SOMETHING THAT NO
ONE'S DONE BEFORE.
I LOVE TO BE AT THEFOREFRONT OF
THINGS.
AND THE OPPORTUNITY TO BUILD
THINGS IS WHAT I DREAM ABOUT
WITH MY EYES OPEN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
&gt;&gt; ANYTIME A COMPANY GETS
BIGGER, I THINK YOU FEAR THE
PERCEPTION THAT YOU'VE BECOME
TOO BIG FOR YOUR BRITCHES OR
THAT YOU'VE CHANGED.
WE'RE GROWING, AND WE ARE A
CORPORATION.
AND THE WORD "CORPORATION" --
THE ROOT WORD IS "CORPUS,"WHICH
IS "BODY."
I'M JUST A PART OF THIS BIGGER
BODY NOW.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WE CAN FIT OUR ENTIRE FIRST
BREWERY IN THIS TANK,OUR ENTIRE
SECOND BREWERY IN THIS TANK,OUR
FIRST BOTTLING LINE IN THIS
TANK, AND PROBABLY THE DELIVERY
TRUCK THAT WE USED TO USE, AS
WELL.
IT'S PRETTY AMAZING.
THIS MACHINE -- TO PARAPHRASE
WOODY GUTHRIE, THIS MACHINE
KILLS FASCIST BEER STYLES.
AND THERE'S HUNDREDS JUST LIKE
IT IN AMERICA.
THEY'RE A, YOU KNOW, DIFFERENT
SIZE AND DIFFERENT SCALE, BUT
THEY ALL REALLY HAVE THE SAME
FUNCTION, WHICH IS PUTTING A
HURTING ON THE BLAND DOMESTIC
LAGERS THAT DOMINATE AMERICAN
BEER CULTURE.
UM, I DREAMED ABOUT WHEN I WAS
OPENING THE BREWERY.
I'VE EXCEED THAT DREAM.
WHOOPS.
SHOULD I DO THIS AND JUST HANG
UP?
&gt;&gt; Baron: GO ON,JUST ANSWER IT.
&gt;&gt; I JUST WANT TOSEE WHO IT IS .
DOGFISH.
HI.
SAM.
WE HAVE OUR 800 NUMBER ON LIKE
ALL OUR FOUR-PACKS AND
SIX-PACKS.
AND YOU COME IN ON MONDAY
MORNING.
THERE'S ALWAYS LIKE SEVEN OR
EIGHT MESSAGE, PEOPLE LIKE,
"DUDE, I'M DRINKING YOUR BEER.
I LOVE IT."
AND YOU'RE LOVING IT?
AND YOU'RE JUST WHAT?
ALL RIGHT, AND YOU -- WHAT? --
YOU SAW THE 800 NUMBER AND
DECIDED TO CALL IT?
OH, WHAT TO DO IS E-MAIL ME.
I'M sam@dogfish.com.
BECAUSE -- OH, NO, IF YOU CARE
ABOUT CALORIES, UH --
OH, THAT'S THE SPIRIT.
FORGET CALORIES.
LIFE'S TOO SHORT TO DRINK LIGHT
BEER.
RIGHT?
AMEN, SISTER.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
PEOPLE ARE CHOOSING TO
SUPPORT SMALLCOMPANIES THAT ARE
ON A HUMAN SCALE.
BIG COMPANIES -- THEY CAN TALK
AT THE CONSUMER, BUT THEY CAN'T
TALK WITH THE CONSUMER.
THE SUCCESSFUL, SMALL BREWERIES
HAVE SOUL.
THESE PEOPLE ARE ALL EQUALLY
SOULFUL, AND I'M JUST HAPPY TO
BE A PART OF THAT.
&gt;&gt; WHAT'S BIG WILL BE GETTING
BIGGER.
MILLER AND COORS ARE JOINING
FORCES, MERGING 50-50.
MILLER SAYS THE GOAL IS TO TAKE
ON BREWERY GIANTANHEUSER-BUSCH.
&gt;&gt; Baron: EVEN THESE TWO GIANTS
HAD TO DO SOMETHING DRASTIC TO
FIGHT ANHEUSER-BUSCH.
AND THEN THE UNTHINKABLE
HAPPENED.
&gt;&gt; LOOKS LIKETHERE'S A NEW KING
OF BEERS.
ANHEUSER-BUSCH, WHICH MAKES
BUDWEISER AND BUD LIGHT, HAS
AGREED TO A TAKEOVER BID FROM
InBev.
&gt;&gt; ANHEUSER-BUSCH INITIALLY
RESISTED THE BUYOUT,BUT FINALLY
SAID, "BOTTOMS UP," WHEN InBev
SWEETENED THE OFFER TO $52
BILLION.
&gt;&gt; IF SHAREHOLDERS AND
REGULATORS OKAY THE DEAL, IT
WOULD CREATE THEWORLD'S LARGEST
BREWER, WITH THE NAME
ANHEUSER-BUSCH InBev.
&gt;&gt; PROGRESS CAN'TSTAND STILL IN
A BUSINESS ANY MORE THAN IN A
NATION.
IN PLANNING BOLDLY FOR THE
FUTURE, WE'RE MERELY IN STEP
WITH THE SPIRIT OF ENTERPRISE,
THE SPIRIT THAT MADEOUT COUNTRY
GREAT.
&gt;&gt; Baron: SO, WHAT'S NEXT FOR
AMERICA?
&gt;&gt; ♪ THEY SAY I'M TOO YOUNG TO
TALK ABOUT ALWAYS ♪
♪ BUT I'LL ALWAYS REMEMBER
TODAY ♪
&gt;&gt; Baron: HISTORY IS SHOWING US
THAT BIG BUSINESS MIXED WITH
POLITICS IS A DANGEROUS BREW.
&gt;&gt; ♪ BUT THIS IS FOREVER ♪
&gt;&gt; Baron: HOW CAN INDEPENDENT
BREWERS LIKE SAM AND RHONDA
COMPETE ON A LEVEL PLAYING
FIELD?
&gt;&gt; ♪ BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN I
CAN'T PLAY ♪
♪ IT FEELS LIKE I'VE WAITED
FOREVER TO GET HERE ♪
♪ BUT THIS IS FOREVER ♪
&gt;&gt; Baron: WHEN DO WESTOP PAYING
LIP SERVICE TO FREE ENTERPRISE
AND ACTUALLY PRACTICE IT?
WHEN IT'S TIME FOR A BEER, WILL
YOU BE ABLE TO CHOOSE THE ONE
THAT YOU WANT?
[ DANIELIA COTTON'S "BANG MY
DRUM" PLAYS ]
&gt;&gt; ♪ EVERYBODY'S GOT SOMETHING
THAT THEY CAN THROW AWAY ♪
♪ 'CAUSE SOMETIMES EVERYBODY'S
GOT WAY TOO MUCH TO SAY ♪
♪ AND I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN THE NIGHTBECOMES THE DAY ♪
♪ BUT I KNOW EVERYTIME I'M LOS T
I ALWAYS FIND MY WAY ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S ABOUT SURVIVAL ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T PUSH ME DOWN 'CAUSE
I'LL JUST STAND UP ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T FOOL ME TWICE WITH
ALL YOUR STUFF ♪
♪ I'LL JUST GIVE IT BACK TO
WHERE IT CAME FROM ♪
♪ AND I'LL SING MYSONG AND BANG
MY DRUM ♪
♪ AND WHAT COMES AROUND IS WHAT
CAME BEFORE ♪
♪ AND I WON'T GETCAUGHT IN YOUR
REVOLVING DOOR ♪
♪ I'LL JUST GIVE IT BACK TO
WHERE IT CAME FROM ♪
♪ AND I'LL SING MY SONG ♪
♪ AND BANG MY DRUM ♪
♪ OH, OH, YEAH ♪
[ INSTRUMENTAL BREAK ]
♪ I WOKE UP THIS MORNIN' ♪
♪ WALKIN' IN THE SUN ♪
♪ I WAS UNDERNEATH A SHADOW ♪
♪ BUT NOT UNDER THE GUN ♪
♪ AND I THOUGHT IWAS FINISHED ♪
♪ I WAS SURE THAT I WAS DONE ♪
♪ I GUESS I'M NOT DEFEATED
'CAUSE IT TURNED OUT THAT I
WON ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IT'S ABOUT SURVIVAL ♪
♪ OH, OH ♪
♪ I'LL JUST GIVE IT BACK TO
WHERE IT CAME FROM ♪
♪ AND I'LL SING MY SONG ♪
♪ AND BANG MY DRUM ♪
♪ BANG MY DRUM ♪
♪ OH, OH ♪